Alpa Chino!
阿尔帕・奇诺！ （和阿尔・帕奇诺谐音，Chino意为棉裤）
We're loaded
我们醉得疯狂
I love the pussy, hell, yeah
我爱BB，哦耶
I love that pussy dripping down to the floor, oh, no
我爱 向地上流水的BB
The wettest pussy, hell, yeah I love the pussy, hell, yeah
我爱最湿的BB，我爱BB，耶
I'm drinking up your Booty Sweat and busting a nut
我要喝干PP流的香汗 达到高潮
Alpa Chino got that pussy control
阿尔帕・奇诺 他操控了BB
Alpa Chino's Booty Sweat.
阿尔帕・奇诺代言的PP香汗能量饮料
Pop an ass open!
张开你的PP迎接吧
Booty Sweat and Bust-A-Nut bars available at concessions now.
“PP香汗能量饮料”和“高潮坚果棒” 特许经营店现已销售
In 2013, when the Earth's rotation came to a halt...
2013年的地球，忽然就不转了…
The President has declared all of North America a disaster area.
总统宣布，整个北美都是灾区
I call on my fellow Americans to come together...
“我号召大伙团结一心…”
... the world called on the one man who could make a difference.
人们呼唤着能够拯救世界的英雄…
When it happened again, the world called on him once more.
当地球又不转了，他又来了
And no one saw it coming three more times!
可谁也没想到，他又来了3次！ （《热天总动员》3，4，5）
Now,
现在
the one man who made a difference five times before,
那个曾经5次拯救世界的男人
is about to make a difference again.
再度归来，改变世界！
Only this time, it's different.
不过这次，有所不同
Who left the fridge open?
是谁没关冰箱门？
Tugg Speedman.
由 奋力・快男 主演
Scorcher Vl: Global Meltdown.
《热天总动员6》之全球消融！
Here we go again.
再次开始吧
Again.
再来（冬季上映）
Will there be anything else?
您还要点什么？
Yes, my dear man. More beans.
我的帅哥，再来点豆子
Granny!
奶奶！
Please!
真不敢相信！
This summer, America's favorite obese family is back.
今夏，美国人气最旺的肥肥一家再次亮相
Gross!
真恶心！
- You're just mad 'cause I'm skinny. - Am not!
- 看我比你瘦，不爽了吧 - 才不是呢
Jeff Portnoy.
杰夫・波特牛 扮演
And Jeff Portnoy are The Fatties: Fart Two.
杰夫・波特牛主演的 肥仔之家 第2屁
In some countries,
在一些国家
it's considered a compliment.
对你放屁是种赞美
Letting loose this summer.
今夏释放
In a time where to be different was to be condemned,
曾几何时，离经叛道就意味着被定罪
and to be condemned was to die,
而被定罪就意味着面临死亡
one man chose to question his God.
而他，选择去质疑上帝…
From Fox Searchlight,
由福克斯探照灯出品
five-time Academy Award winner Kirk Lazarus
5次奥斯卡奖得主 柯克・拉扎勒斯 （Kirk:教堂；Lazarus:圣经中死而复生的人物）
and MTV Movie Award Best Kiss winner Tobey Maguire.
和MTV最佳亲吻奖得主 托比・马奎尔
Winner of the Beijing Film Festival's coveted Crying Monkey Award,
夺得北京电影节最让人梦寐以求的泣猴奖
Satan's Alley.
《恶魔小径》
I've been a bad, bad boy, Father.
神父，我是个坏小孩，非常坏 （金秋上映）
In the winter of 1969,
1969年的冬天
an elite force of the U. S. Army
美军的一支精英小队
was sent on a top-secret assignment in southeast Vietnam.
前往越南东南部执行绝密任务
The objective, rescue Sergeant Four Leaf Tayback
目标是救出 四叶・泰背 中士
from a heavily guarded NVA Prison Camp.
地点是守卫森严的越军战俘集中营
The mission was considered to be near suicide.
这可以称得上是自杀行动
Of the 10 men sent, four returned.
派出去十个人，只有四人生还
Of those four, three wrote books about what happened.
四人之中，三个人将经历写成了书
Of those three, two were published.
三人之中，两个人成功出版
Of those two, just one got a movie deal.
两人之中，只有一人拿到了拍成电影的合同
This is the story of the men who attempted to make that movie.
接下来的故事，讲的就是拍那部电影的人们
Whisky Fire Old Snake requests an LZ prep
威士忌火蛇号 请求准备降落点
at Alpha-Delta-two-four-eight-niner, over.
位置是甲丁2489，完毕
Floyd, this is lead. Right echelon approach from RP to LZ, acknowledge.
福德号，这是领头飞机 右梯队从指定地点前往降落点，收到回话
Floyd, Wall-Eye airborne. Welcome aboard.
福德号，斜眼号空降队，欢迎加入
All right, lead's going in. Give her some cover.
好了，领头飞机过来了，给它点掩护
Delivery on five. I repeat, delivery on five.
从偏后方发射，重复，从偏后方发射
This is Zero-Three. I'm on your six, don't worry.
这是03号，我在你正后方，别担心
Chalk-Three's taking fire. Guns right, guns right.
粉笔3号受到攻击，向右开火，向右开火
Lay that shit down!
快把这破玩意降下来
Come on!
快点！
Come on, you damn dirty heathens!
来啊，你们这群粗野的异教徒！
Fats! Run your motherfucking ass over there,
胖子，快他妈的给我跑到那边去
hold these men off, now!
赶快拖住那帮混蛋
We're fixing to lift off!
我们马上就要准备起飞了
Put some pep in your step, dick! Jelly-ass bitch!
走路带点精神气！你个屁股没缝的混蛋
Wall-Eye, Wall-Eye, this is Boomer One-Seven in the Zee!
呼叫斜眼号，我是Z区投弹兵17号
I need fast movers on my Yankee Smoke, copy?
请速派飞机过来投放炸弹，收到？
Boomer, this is Wall-Eye. I got two-Alpha-four
呼叫投弹兵，斜眼收到，2甲4型蛇颈导弹…
- snake and nape on the ready! - Oh, Jesus! Holy shit!
- …准备完毕 - 我的天哪！我靠！
Holy shit!
我靠！
Get on that horn and get some firepower, boy!
小子，你去拿话筒再要点火力过来
Jesus Christ!
我的天哪
Listen, you cherry fuck,
听着，你没破处的小崽儿
you call in that snake and nape and get us some boom-boom now!
快给我呼叫蛇颈导弹，来点轰炸！
I'd do it myself but I'm kind of goddamn busy!
我也想去，可我他妈的正忙！
I need an answer, Boomer!
投弹兵请回话
Wall-Eye, Wall-Eye!
斜眼斜眼！
I copy!
我收到了
We got beaucoup zips in the zee.
我们在Z区受到激烈攻击
Rock and roll!
尽快轰炸！
What the fuck?
这他妈的是怎么回事？
That's for Brooklyn, motherfucker!
这是给布鲁克林报仇，王八蛋！
I think I can put it back in!
我想我能把这塞回去
We got to get back to the bird.
咱们快点回飞机上去
Lukemeyer's got popped!
他的肚子被人爆了
This is the last Christmas I spend with Victor Charlie up my ass!
这个圣诞节是你们越军 最后一次当我的跟屁虫的机会了
Want some? Get some!
想来点吗？吃我一棒吧！
Hey, yo, Fats! I ain't seen Four Leaf!
你，胖子，我没看见四叶的人影！
Don't count him out! That bastard's got luck tattooed to his ass!
别把他丢了！那杂种的屁股上都纹了幸运符
Motown, get your Detroit jukebox Jheri curl ass
底特律，快点挪动你的卷毛屁股
in this chickenshit chop-chop! ASAFP!
给我滚上这鸡屎飞机来，他妈的快点
Four Leaf is still outside the perimeter, Sarge!
四叶还在防线外面啊，中士！
Miss me with that cracker chump jive! We di di mau! We di di mau!
不管那个单薄小屁妞了，咱们快走（越南话）
Come on, Sarge. Stop jiving. Four Leaf is there.
中士，别说胡话了，四叶还在那边呢
Dead meat, soldier!
想找死吗，士兵
Or do you want to be a hero?
还是想冒充英雄？
That's just how Brooks got his Jew ass killed, man.
犹太佬布鲁克林就是这么没命的
And Meatball's dago ass bought the six-by-three farm.
外号“肉团”的家伙也这么挂了
Now get your ass up in the Huey, before I stomp a trench in your hiney hole!
赶快滚上休伊直升机 要不我把你屁股踩出个大坑
Come on, get down, get down!
快点，卧倒，卧倒
What am I looking at? What is this?
我眼前这是…啥吗东西？
Come on, let's get, let's go! Come on, elevator up, up!
快点，收摊走人了，升空起飞！
Sarge. It's Four Leaf.
中士，那是四叶！
No!
不！
You get out of that hole!
从那坑里逃出来啊！
You make it home, now.
马上你就能回家了！
Survive!
挺住！
I hope y'all like hamburger meat.
希望你们受得了汉堡包里的生肉
'Cause that's exactly what I'm gonna be bringing back
因为我马上要带回飞机的东西
and serving up in this whirly bird.
就是一堆活人肉了
Cover me, you limp dick fuckups!
掩护我，你们这帮硬不起来的笨蛋！
Peek-a-boo! I see you!
跟我藏猫猫？看着你了
Hold on, Four Leaf!
坚持住，四叶！
Oh, shit!
我靠！
Watch my right!
注意我右边！
Fuck you, Charlie!
去死吧，越南佬！
Come on, Leaf, let's boogie!
来吧叶子，扭着走也要回去
No!
不！
- Fats! - Holy fuck!
- 胖子！ - 我靠啊！
Take us over to those men! Shit!
别在他们头上转悠！我靠
Look at you, man. Playing with grenades.
瞧瞧你，敢拿手榴弹玩杂技
I'm cold, Linc.
我身体冰凉，小林
I can't feel my legs.
我的大腿没知觉了
Ain't nothing but a thang.
也就蹭破了点皮
Hey, Linc.
小林
What, man?
想说什么，伙计？
Why does man
为什么人们把棍子…
got to pick up sticks against another man?
当作武器杀害别人
Instead of using them sticks to
而不是给别人…
I'll never know.
我也弄不明白
Hold my hands,
握紧我的手
'cause I got something to...
我有话…
I got something to say.
我有话要说
Oh, boy.
乖乖！
- You holding 'em? - I got 'em tight.
- 你握住了？ - 握紧了
When we get back to the world,
等咱们回去了
we gonna put together that three-piece combo band we talked about?
要把咱们商量好的三人爵士乐团组织起来
- Me on stand-up bass. - Johnny on drums.
- 我弹低音吉他 - 约翰尼打鼓
And me tickling the ivories.
我负责弹钢琴
I ain't never been worth a nothing in this life,
我这一辈子一事无成
but I want you to know something.
…可我想跟你说
What, man?
什么 哥们？
You are my...
你是我的…
You are my brother.
你是我兄弟
You are my... You are my...
你是我兄弟，你是…你是我…
I am your brother.
我是你的兄弟
I'm sorry. Could we cut?
抱歉，咱们停下行吗
- What's he saying? - Damien, can we cut?
- 他说什么？ - 达门，暂停行吗
- No. No, no, no, no, no... - All right, you know what?
- 不行不行… - 得了，你得明白…
We got the jets coming in, big explosion, two minutes.
再过2分钟，飞机就要过来弄个大爆炸场面了
Still rolling.
继续拍下去
You know what? No, not still rolling. Can we cut?
我看算了，别拍了，暂停好吗？
- We're cutting. - No, we're not. Get out!
- 咱们别拍了 - 不，没停拍，快点
Hey, what's going on? For real, my butt is hurting!
怎么不动了？我屁股可疼死了
This harness is riding up my crack!
吊具卡到我屁股缝里了！
- Damien, are we cutting? - No! No! Still rolling!
- 达门，暂停了吗？ - 没有，还在拍呢！
Mr. Cockburn! Are we cutting, sir?
考蛋先生！停拍了吗？ （《热带惊雷》外景地，越南广治省）
No! No. I'm not cutting! We're still rolling!
没停没停！还在拍摄！
Damien, what's the dealy, dude?
达门，你什么指示？ （《热带惊雷》外景地，越南广治省）
Are we gonna blow this tree line or what?
还要不要炸飞这排树？
Tuk Tuk and Kim got the blue balls here.
他俩把忍了一年的蛋蛋们都拿来了
I'm gonna let them squirt if we're a go!
一声令下，马上射飞！
- Play it through. Still rolling! - Dieter, can he hear me?
- 继续演，还在拍呢 - 迪特，听得见我吧？
That's C-4, dipshit. Put that back. I said a detonator.
笨蛋，这是C4炸药，快放回去 我要的是雷管
I need some dudes up here who speak American, God damn it!
我需要些懂英语的家伙，真见鬼
He's making a fucking sweater back here.
他拿这些电线织毛衣呢
I'm trying to put Tiger Balm on this jungle's nuts.
我正等着把神油抹在丛林的蛋蛋上呢
Everyone, please shut up.
大伙都安静点
The jets are coming in. We only have one chance at this!
飞机马上就过来了，必须一次就拍摄成功！
And go!
开拍
Let's do it. You feel it? You feel me?
开始吧，情绪来了吗？明白我的意思？
- You are my... - I am your brother.
- 你是我… - 我是你兄弟
We've seen it all, man.
咱俩患难一场…
I'm sorry, Damien?
抱歉，达门
Are you seeing that?
你看见了吗？
The little froggy on the boom mike? It's right in my eyeline.
吊杆麦克风上的小青蛙都到我眼睛这里了
Donny! What's up, man?
东尼，什么事儿？
It's been there the whole show.
从开始拍片，它就一直在那儿
Yeah, well it's right in my face,
是啊，可现在正对着我的脸
I'm staring at a frog, I'm trying to feel...
我盯着青蛙，还要感觉到…
It's always the yellow frog that brings them black frog on Fridays, man.
该周末了，你也要允许人家黄青蛙 找黑色蛙来点乐子吧
Hell, no, I didn't pee on that girl.
瞎扯！我才没有在那女孩身上撒尿
No, I didn't pee on her, listen, listen, listen, listen. No, no.
我没朝她身上撒尿，你听我说
The story is this. She was in the way when I was peeing, she walked past.
实际情况是，我撒尿的时候她正好走过去
What the fuck is going on here?
现在他妈的是怎么回事？
On three, baby. One, two, breathe.
宝贝，我数3下，1…2…呼吸
Look, do me a favor. I don't want to do a countdown before I do the scene.
帮个忙好吗？我不想每次都倒计时
- No countdown? - No countdown.
- 不倒计时？ - 不倒计时
- Okay. - Can we just do it off of "Action"?
- 好吧 - 那说“开拍”好了
Just... ln your own time.
算了…你跟着感觉走吧
- Good... - I'm not a rocket ship, okay?
- 好 - 又不是要发射火箭
- All right, dude. - And action!
- 得了，伙计们 - 开拍！
Whatever floats your boat, baby. Fuck! Don't die!
不管想什么办法，靠！别死！
Erika, get me a Vitamin Water!
给我瓶维他命水！
You know what it is, Damien? I'm sorry.
知道么，达门，我先道歉
Not to get into his thing, but if I'm crying, should Osiris be crying, too?
我不是要管他的事，可我哭了他也要哭？
- No, it's everyone cry... - We cutting or we crying?
- 都要哭… - 停拍还是接着哭？
- No, no, no, we're crying! - Just call it, man!
- 不不不，接着哭 - 停拍得了！
- Kirk, you can cry. Tugg, you can cry. - Thanks!
- 柯克你要哭，奋力也哭 - 谢谢
- Everybody cry... - You know what?
- 两人都要哭… - 其实…
- You see how agitated he is now? - I know.
- 你看他的情绪也上来了 - 确实
- Let's make lemonade. Let's go to work. - Okay. Still rolling!
- 我俩再挤出点酸水吧 - 好，继续拍！
This is Falcon One. We have the ridge in sight, approximately two miles out.
这里是猎鹰一号，已经看见山脊 估计还有3公里
Dieter, these jets are about to crest this ridge line.
迪特，飞机马上就要飞过山脊了
They got about 200 pounds of shit your pants.
带着90多公斤炸药让你爽
I need to know if we're ready to go.
准备好了告诉我
- You're my... You're my... - I am your...
- 你是我的…我的 - 我是你的…
See, that's what I think it is, Damien. I think it's the line.
总算搞明白了，达门，是台词的问题
Yeah?
是吗？
I don't know if Four Leaf would say that... Four Leaf?
我想四叶他…四叶？
Were you crying when your hands blew up?
你手被炸飞了还会哭出来吗？
No. See, he didn't. Yeah, I mean, just that's what...
你看他摇头了，这样才符合…
So now we in re-writes, right?
现在要重写剧本了？
- Where you going? - Let's re-write it!
- 你上哪去？ - 那咱们重写好了
Action Jackson can't cry. That's what's going down.
牛B主角不会哭，这么写好了
You know what, Kirk? I'm ready to do the scene!
柯克你别走了，我已经准备好拍这镜头了
What scene? The scene is about emotionality. Where is it?
这个镜头？这段是情感戏，你感情呢？
- Now it's time to flip the script! - Kirk...
- 那现在你们就改剧本吧！ - 柯克…
Be here till Chinese New Year waiting for my man to cry.
就算等到过春节了，这老兄也哭不出来
You're tangling me, you're fucking tangling me.
你们把我缠住了，他妈的缠住了
You're tangling me, God damn it!
缠住我了，该死
- Kirk, no! - Stop tailgating me, you pasty tea bag!
- 柯克，不行！ - 少背后放冷枪，你个舔人卵蛋的小白脸
I'm going potty. You want to hold my dick?
我去洗手间，你想握住我的小弟弟吗？
Shit! What are you fucking both doing, Good Lord!
靠！你俩在这儿捣什么乱呢！
We're getting this in a wide shot, right?
咱们这是要拍宽景镜头吧？
Of course we're getting it in a fucking wide.
当然要拍宽景
What, do you think I'm a dick or something?
你当我白痴啊？
Get that fucking food...
把这些吃的…
Here they come!
飞机来了！
- The planes are inbound! - Shit! Shit!
- 飞机来了 - 我靠！我靠！
Shit, shit, cocksucker, bollocks. Tropic tits!
靠！杂种！狗屁！热带乳头！
That's the signal! Go, go, go, go, go!
信号来了！开始，开始！
Let's go freaking Tet here!
咱们来个越南春节的狂欢吧
Goddamn shit-picking cock!
他妈的踩屎的JB！
That's my shit!
我的杰作！
Mother Nature just pissed her pantsuit!
大地母亲刚被吓得尿了裤子！
- Sweet. - Oh, mama!
- 场面不错 - 我的妈呀
Bungle in the jungle.
“丛林里面一团糟”
More bad news from the Vietnamese set of Tropic Thunder,
《热带惊雷》在越南外景地传来更多坏消息
where a $4 million explosion charred the Asian location
花了4百万美元把树林炸成焦土
and the camera wasn't even rolling.
摄像机居然没有开拍
Financed by hotheaded mega-mogul Les Grossman,
由急性子大亨 雷斯・格罗斯曼 投资 (Les俚语里意思是拉拉，grossman粗人)
the film is already rumored to be one month behind schedule
才拍摄了5天，就有传言说电影会比原计划…
just five days into shooting. The reason?
…拖后1个月，要问原因？
Fingers are pointed at rookie director Damien Cockburn,
新手导演 达门・考蛋 是千夫所指
who, insiders say, can't control a star-studded cast,
知情人透露，他根本镇不住这些明星
including flatulent star of the popular Fatties franchise, Jeff Portnoy.
其中有超人气浮夸影星 肥胖大仙 杰夫・波特牛
Let me tell you something. A lot of people are disrespecting me.
我告诉你们，很多人都瞧不起我
They say that the movie's just about farts. It's about family,
说这电影就是放屁 其实它是家庭片
and... you! You can't do what I do.
去你妈的！你们可没我放屁的本事
Fresh from his most recent arrest for heroin, glue and crack possession,
因为私藏各种毒品的罪名，他新近才被释放
Portnoy was almost uninsurable.
波特牛现在可是最不靠谱
Also in the mix is Booty Sweat-hocking hip-hop hyphenate Alpa Chino.
还有代言PP香汗饮料的 说唱歌手阿尔帕・奇诺
I'm so excited, you know what I'm saying, about doing Tropic Thunder.
能来拍热带惊雷，我激动死了
Hey, drink Booty Sweat, baby. Drink Booty Sweat.
宝贝，别忘了喝PP香汗饮料！
But the real heavyweight on the set
而演员当中真正重量级的…
is five-time Academy Award winner Kirk Lazarus.
是5次奥斯卡奖得主 柯克・拉扎勒斯
The brilliant Australian known for his bad boy antics off-screen
这个天才澳洲人，生活中一副坏小子形象
is famous for his total immersion into any role he portrays.
因为非常入戏而闻名
Well, being an actor is no different
演员也一样
than being a rugby player or a construction worker,
和橄榄球、盖楼没区别
save for the fact that my tools
虽说我善于…
are the mechanisms that trigger human emotion.
打动观众内心
Lazarus underwent a controversial
拉扎勒斯最近的手术广受争议
pigmentation alteration procedure in order to play
他将皮肤染色
the platoon's African-American sergeant, Lincoln Osiris.
就为了演好黑人角色，林肯・奥西里斯 （Osiris埃及神话中的冥王）
Yeah!
耶！
Trying to hold his own onscreen with Kirk
当然还有过气的…
is action juggernaut Tugg Speedman.
动作影星 奋力・快男
Once the highest grossing star in the world,
曾是全球收入最高的影星
lately his Scorcher films have lost their heat.
不过《热天总动员》系列要降温了
Recently, Speedman opened up to Tyra.
最近，快男对蒂拉敞开了心扉
You have no real family.
你没有真正的家庭
You're on the wrong side of 40. You're childless and alone.
四十不惑了还在走着下坡路，没有孩子
Somebody close to you said,
你一个朋友说
"One more flop and it's over. "
“再跌个跟头，这辈子就完了”
Somebody said they were close to me?
有人说是我朋友？
It's been a tough year for Tugg.
他今年很不容易
The disappointing buddy comedy Chitlin' & the Dude
先是无聊的友情喜剧《剧院伙计》
was followed by an ill-advised venture into serious dramatic territory.
然后头脑发热非要向演技派发展
Simple Jack,
《笨蛋杰克》
the story of a mentally impaired farmhand who can talk to animals,
讲述一个弱智农场工人，还能和动物对话
was a box office disaster
成了票房毒药
that many critics called, "One of the worst movies of all time. "
许多评论家称之为“有史以来最糟糕的电影”
I ain't got a good brain.
我脑子不…了…了…灵
I think you've got a fine brain, Jack.
我觉得你的脑子很好用，杰克！
You make me happy.
你…日…日…日…让…让我开心
But now the question is, can Speedman make audiences happy
可是快男能日…让…观众们开心吗？
in what's being called the most expensive
这最费钱的战争片…
- war movie never made? - Rick Peck.
- …好像永远拍不出来了？ - 瑞克・佩克找你
Wishing Tugg all the best on that one.
祝他好运吧
Rum-Tum-Tuggernauts, it's the Pecker. You got time for your agent?
公子哥奋力，我是佩克 有时间和经纪人聊聊吗？
- Rick? - Hey, buddy,
- 瑞克？ - 是我，伙计
guess who I'm staring at right now.
猜猜我正看着谁？
- What? - I'm looking at your ugly mug
- 什么？ - 看着你的丑脸
on the back cover of Vanity Fair magazine,
名利场杂志的封底
holding a cute, cuddly panda from Cutesville.
抱着个可爱的熊猫，给可爱村做广告
It is insane, bro. You are a rock star.
你真牛啊，跟摇滚明星似的
Hey, did you get the gift basket I sent?
收到你的礼物篮了吗？
From Rick.
他送的
Yeah. Yeah. It's cool, man. Thanks.
是啊，很不错，谢谢你
All right, that is a real satellite phone, bro.
老兄，那是货真价实的卫星电话
Do not re-gift.
别随便就转手送人
Hey. You see that Access Hollywood piece?
你看刚才的“直击好莱坞”节目了？
Yeah, I did. It was like pistol-whipping a blind kid.
看了，好像在拿手枪抽盲童
I mean, I'm not gonna sugarcoat it, Tugg. You are a huge star, all right?
我不用安慰你，你本来就是大明星
But right now,
不过现在
you're like that kid on the playground, you know,
你就是球场上的那小孩
the one who has lice that none of the other kids want to play with?
头上长虱子，没人愿意和你玩
- What do you mean? - I mean we gotta shave your head
- 什么意思？ - 你要洗心革面
and get you back on the monkey bars, right?
就能回到滑梯上爽了
What?
啥？
How did the crying scene go?
你那场哭戏怎么样
Horrible. Lazarus started crying.
糟透了，拉扎勒斯也跟着哭
Then he starts drooling and dribbling, and it wasn't even in the script...
口水流我一身，剧本就没这么写！
Stop right there!
别抱怨了！
You gotta buck up here, Tuggboat.
振奋起来，拖船 （拖船是英文里的奋力+船）
Who cares how much more talented he may be than you?
谁在乎他是否更有才？
If he cries, you cry harder, man.
他要哭，你就哭得更狠！
Didn't your dog have, like, leukemia or something
小时候你的狗得过白血病吗？
when you were a kid? I mean, think of that.
想一想就哭出来了
Boom! End of story. They hook up the TiVo yet?
搞定！他们接好“替你录”了吗？ （TiVo:录电视节目的数字视频录放机）
Good gosh.
天哪
- What? - The TiVo, they hook it up?
- 什么？ - “替你录”，他们接好了吗？
- No. The guy didn't come. - What?
- 没有，人都没来 - 什么？
For fuck's sake, that is unacceptable.
他妈的老天啊，这可不能容忍
They have digital cable, but, I mean, it's okay.
他们有数字电视，我觉得够了
No, no, no. Come on, man. It's not okay.
不行，这可不行
It is not okay, Tugg!
这可是大事儿，奋力！
And you don't need to explain to me why you need TiVo
你都不用向我解释为什么你需要“替你录”
or clean water, clean sheets, food, shelter.
或是纯净水啊，床单啊，食物帐篷之类的
I mean, I fought for that in your contract.
在合同里帮你搞定这些是我份内的事
How's the adoption thing coming, buddy?
对了，你收养小孩的事情怎么样了？
Not too great.
不怎么样
I feel like all the good ones are gone.
我感觉好小孩都被人挑走了
Well, at least you get to choose yours.
至少你还有得选
I'm stuck with mine.
我是没得挑了
Tell you what, get back to work, genius soldier.
你快回去工作吧，天才战士
The Pecker's on a TiVo mission for the Y-O-U.
“替你录”这事儿，我佩克帮你搞定！
Work on those tears, my man.
练练掉眼泪，伙计
All right. Yeah.
好吧
Say it for me one time.
再跟我说一遍
- You make me happy. - Make me happy.
- 你日…日…让我开心
- I love you, buddy. - All right, bye.
- 哥们没说的 - 好的，再见
Crisis meeting? What does that mean, exactly?
紧急会议？搞什么鬼？
I mean, are we in a crisis?
咱们有紧急危机了吗？
He's the head of the studio.
他是电影公司的老大
He's reaching out. We're 10,000 miles away.
不过摸不着咱们，离着1万6千公里远呢
He just wants a little face-time.
也就想来个小会面
I know, it's just you said that he called it a crisis meeting. So...
我知道，可你说他要开紧急会议…所以…
It's Les Grossman. He throws these words around.
他可是雷斯・格罗斯曼，爱用夸张的词儿
"Crisis, " "explosion, " "not rolling, " "fired. "
“紧急”、“爆发”、“停机”、“解雇”之类的
These are just words.
随便说说
Yeah! Yeah!
爽啊！爽！
Keep a secret? A camera truck in London just ploughed into Judi Dench.
替我保密啊，他的摄影车刚把朱迪・丹奇给撞了 （朱迪・丹奇是演技派女影星，007里的M夫人）
Trust me, he's got bigger problems.
相信我，他还有更操心的事儿
Look, he may be able to see me, but I can't see him.
他可能看得见我，但我看不见他
- Move! Move! Hello, Les! Hello! - Get your ass out of my...
- 让开让开！雷斯您好 - 从我眼前滚开…
I don't know why we don't have...
为什么我们没有…
Get him a Diet Coke. Les! It's working!
给他健怡可乐，雷斯，好了！
Yeah, whatever you're doing right there. Hello, Les!
是啊，不管你怎么搞的
- Hello, Les! - Okay.
- 你好，雷斯！ - 你好
We got you loud and clear here, Les.
我们听你说话非常清楚
I see you. I see you. I see you.
让我看看你们…
Which one of you fuckfaces is Damien Cockburn?
哪个欠揍的是 达门・考蛋？
That's me, sir.
是我，先生
It's good to finally meet you at last, get some face-time.
咱们总算见着面了
And who here is the key grip? You? You.
置景主任是谁？你？就你
Hit that director in the face, really fucking hard.
对着导演的脸，给我狠狠地打
Sorry, man.
抱歉，老兄
This is your fault, you limey fuck!
这是你的错，你个英国傻B
You shit the money-bed, my friend.
你把我的钱都给扔粪坑了
- What? - God damn it, Damien!
- 什么？ - 该死，达门！
With all due respect, Les Grossman did not blow up the jungle.
我直说吧，是你而不是雷斯炸的丛林
- What? - Fuck the jungle.
- 什么？ - 去他妈的丛林
Exactly!
他说得对！
Come on, man.
想明白点，伙计
Hey, Les, I understand if you're angry,
雷斯，我明白你很生气
but I am dealing with a bunch of prima donnas!
可这里的一群娘娘腔不好伺候
Clowns! Tugg Speedman, he can't cry! He can't cry!
那个小丑，奋力・快男，连哭都不会
You know how you handle an actor? They whine about anything,
知道怎么对付演员吗？只要他们一抱怨
you pull down their pants and you spank their ass.
把他们裤子扒了，照屁股就打
- You spank that ass, Les. - What?
- 狠狠地打，雷斯 - 什么？
Spanking a child turns him into a little snot.
把小孩打到哭成泪人
Fear makes him a man.
被打怕了就成男人了
I know a place where a man's worth is measured
我知道个地方，评价人的价值…
in the ears hanging from his dog tags.
是看脖子上的身份牌串着多少敌人的耳朵 （越战时候的美军这样做过）
The real deep shit.
那才真正磨练人
You wanna make this movie right?
想要拍好电影吗？
That's where you take your pansy-ass actors.
就把这帮娘娘腔演员送到这样的地方
Who is this guy?
他又是谁？
Les, that's Four Leaf.
雷斯，他就是四叶本人
Sergeant Four Leaf Tayback. I wrote the book.
四叶・泰背中士，是我写的书
You're a great American. This nation owes you a huge debt.
你是伟大的美国人，国家也欠你不少
Now shut the fuck up and let me do my job!
不过给我闭上臭嘴，让我干活！
- Look, Cockburn. - Yes.
- 听着，考蛋 - 是
From now on, my fist is gonna be so far up your shithole
从现在开始，我的拳头可是离你屁眼不远了
that every time you have a thought,
以后不管想干什么
it's gonna have to tiptoe past my wedding ring.
都得踮起脚尖做事，小心我带戒指的拳头
Take control of your actors, or I will shut you down.
管好你的演员，要不你就关门走人
Diet Coke!
给我健怡可乐！
One week down, two weeks behind,
才一个星期，计划就落后了两星期
GI Joe can't cry, don't matter 'cause you ain't got the camera turned on anyway.
特种兵哭不出来无所谓 因为镜头盖都没开
Let's party!
还是聚会狂欢吧
Man, you better get your shit straight,
最好把你的这些烂事儿都给摆平了
or I'll be on the next NetJet out of here, baby. You feel me?
否则我坐着下批航班就走人，明白了？
- You feel that? - Yeah.
- 懂了吗？ - 懂了
Here comes another. There we go. Now what?
再提个醒，行了，看看接下来干啥
- Sandusky. Good. - Hey, Mr. Cockburn.
- 三达斯基，你在就好 - 考蛋先生
We need to have a cast meeting right now.
咱们得马上开个演员会议
- Right now? Awesome. - Yes.
- 现在吗？太好了 - 是现在
You actually care, don't you?
你确实很在乎这个机会吧？
Yeah, it's a huge deal for me, are you kidding?
开玩笑吗，对我来说这可是一笔大买卖
I've spent the past two years of my life
我过去两年的生活费
living off residuals from a anti-herpes medication commercial.
靠的是拍抗疱疹广告剩下的钱
I know, you're the only one who auditioned,
我明白，你是唯一通过试镜的人
the only one who did the two-week boot camp.
也只有你参加了两星期新兵训练营
Hey, hey, Alpa.
阿尔帕
I'm the director. He's... I need to speak to my actor.
我是导演…我要和我的演员说句话
All right, hold up. Chino?
好，等着，奇诺？
What? Hell, yo. What's up, baby?
什么事？还好吧，宝贝？
This about the Booty Sweat cross-promotion?
想要给PP香汗饮料交叉促销吗？
No, it's about the film.
不是，我要说电影
Oh, the film and Booty Sweat's the same thing. Give him a shot.
两个是一码事，给他一罐
Hey, how you doing, Jeff?
你还好吗，杰夫？
- Who are you? - That's awesome, man.
- 你是谁？ - 你演得真好
Kevin. Kevin Sandusky. I play Brooklyn, we've been working together.
凯文・三达斯基，我演布鲁克林的角色 咱们一起演的戏
Oh, right, right. I like you.
哦，想起来了，我喜欢你的表演
Man, it's a real honor to be here...
很荣幸能在这儿演出…
I can tell it's gonna be a good experience.
这对你来说会是很不错的经历
I'm really having a good time.
这段时间我过得很充实
Hey, can you help me out, man? I'm looking for this guy.
能帮我个忙吗？我在找一个家伙
The grip with the bandana. He's got a package for me.
戴着大手帕的家伙，有个包裹给我
There he is, fucker. Dragon!
在那儿呢，混蛋，阿龙
What the fuck? Oh, buddy!
搞什么鬼？伙计！
I'm gonna go shoot a video, right?
我要拍一个电视片
I'm gonna have V. C. Soldiers in the video
达门，让片中的越南士兵们…
doing the noodle-legs, Damien.
跳面条舞步
Hell, yeah, do it. V. C. Soldiers doing the hip-hop bunny hop, Damien.
哦耶，越南兵跳嘻哈兔子舞
It's good, I love it, great. But I need to...
主意不错，我很喜欢，不过我要…
V. C. Soldiers doing the seizure, baby. Hit it, baby.
越南兵表演心脏病发作，来吧
Hell yeah, get it. Get it, Cornbread.
哦耶，懂了吧，玉米脑袋？
Alpa!
阿尔帕！
Yo, check it out. Donny on the phone.
接电话，东尼过来的
Hello? Yo, yo, Donny!
喂，你啊，东尼！
Can we call him back? I've got to have a cast meeting.
能待会再打吗？我们要开个演员会
When we put aside our differences,
当我们放下之间的分歧
we see we're kind of the same.
就会发现其实大家差不多
Let's be friends.
让我们做朋友吧
I know we can do great things together.
齐心协力，定成大事
That's a quotation from a children's book I co-wrote,
这是我和别人合写的一本儿童图书 里的一句话
The Boy Everybody Was Jealous Of.
《人人羡慕的小男孩》
I think it pertains to the journey...
我想这个故事适合于…
Simple Jack sucked ass!
笨蛋杰克去舔屁股
All right, who said that? It's not funny.
好了，谁说的？这不好笑
Whoever it is, it's not funny, okay?
不管是谁说的，不好笑
When the herd loses its way,
当羊群迷了路
the shepherd must kill the bull that leads them astray.
牧羊人肯定要杀了乱带路的领头羊
- Four Leaf? - Come on over. It's okay.
- 四叶？ - 过来吧，别怕
- Sit down. - Yes.
- 坐下 - 好
- So, you don't like the hotel? - Beds give me nightmares.
- 你不喜欢住旅馆？ - 睡床上会做噩梦
I'm guessing right about now you couldn't find a Dixie coonskin
我看你这状态，就好比找不到自己的熊皮
with an Ohio hooker holding your prick and showing you the way.
也没有俄亥俄的小姐拉着你的小弟弟领路一样
What?
啥？
You're a riddle
你就像个迷宫
with no cheese to maze through.
没有奶酪的指引出不来了
Don't you get it?
你还不明白吗？
No, I don't. I'm a cock of the mouse or something. I don't know.
不明白，我可能是老鼠的鸡鸡或什么…
I put my story in your limp Brit hands,
我把故事交到了你这英国佬手上
and you are not going to fail me.
你不能让我失望
You think I was just blowing my own bagpipe in that meeting?
你以为今天开会我是在虚张声势？
You must put those boys in the shit.
你得把演员扔到困境里面
What? I don't understand.
什么？我没听明白
- You wanna make your movie or not? - Yes, I do.
- 你到底想不想拍好电影？ - 想啊
All right, you get some of those little video type cameras.
那好，把那些小摄像机都拿出来
We take them out there, and we put them in the trees in different angles.
咱们把它们藏到树底下，对着不同的角度
Then you give me and that pyromaniac Cody
然后把你手里所有的炸药地雷什么的
all the smoke bombs, charges, explosives, detonators you got.
都交给我和那个纵火狂科迪
Then we take those boys up there,
然后咱们就把孩子们扔到野地里
me and Cody, we could light up that fucking jungle,
我和科迪把这林子点着了
so those lily-dick actors would be shitting their pants
那些蔫了吧唧的演员们会屁滚尿流
and screaming for their mammies.
哭着喊妈妈
They'd be begging for a body bag if it means a ride home.
为了能回家，就算呆在运尸袋里也愿意
I could do it.
我可以这么干
I could shoot the whole thing guerrilla style. Gritty, dirty.
能拍成游击队的风格，心狠手辣那种
Get them away from their helpers and ass-licking assistants.
不能让闲人或马屁经纪人帮他们
Put them in the real shit.
你得来真格的！
- Real shit. - With real fear in their eyes!
- 真格的 - 要真的害怕
Real fear, real emotion! Yes, Four Leaf, yes!
真正的恐惧和情感！四叶，太对了
- Yes! Yes!
- 就这么干！
Take them off the fucking grid!
让他们从舒服窝里滚出来！
You are no longer actors in a movie!
你们不再是电影里的演员了
You are five men in a helicopter!
你们是直升飞机里的5个爷们！
With three other men!
外加3个爷们！
How long are we gonna be gone, anyways?
我们要去多久？
'Cause I left most of my vitamins back at the hotel.
我把维生素片忘在旅馆了
- Save your breath, maggots! - That's right, maggots!
- 别费心思了，你个苍蝇蛆 - 他说得对，苍蝇蛆
M&M?
M&M巧克力豆？
Go, go, go! Get out of the chopper!
下去，从直升飞机里下去！
Move it, maggots, move! Move, grunts, move your ass!
快点，苍蝇蛆，动作快点！
Get out, you wriggly worms!
快点，你们这些小虫子
- It's up too high! - Move, move, move!
- 太高了 - 快点
See you in hell!
地狱里见吧
This is bullshit! I gotta at least call my fucking assistant.
真是胡搞，怎么也要给我的经纪人打个电话
Fucking! Jesus! Dude!
我靠！天哪！老兄！
You're sitting on a nest of hostile enemy V. C.
你们现在是在越共军队的老巢里面
Congratulations, Fats. You just got us all killed.
祝贺你，胖子，你这么嚷嚷会把大家都害死
Anybody else care to give away our position to Charlie?
还有人想暴露咱们的位置吗？
Cell phones!
手机！
What the hell, Damien?
你这是干嘛，达门？
Weren't no cell phones in '69, man. I'm head-to-toe legitimate.
1969年可是没手机的，我这一身才配套
Gentlemen, I've got good news and bad news.
先生们，有好消息也有坏消息
The studio wants to shut us down. That's the bad news.
坏消息是电影公司想要让咱们走人
And the good news.
好消息呢…
If you wanna save this movie, you will become a unit.
想要挽救这部电影，大家就齐心协力
Your objective is to head north to the D'ang Kwook River
你们的任务是向北穿过当考河
and liberate the POW camp,
解放战俘营
at which point Four Leaf will get himself captured,
四叶会被关在那里
at which point you will rescue him,
你们要去那里营救
at which point we will chopper you home!
等拍完了就上直升机回家
Damn.
靠啊
Four Leaf, since you're the staff sergeant,
四叶，既然你是头儿
there's the map, this is the scene list.
地图就给你了，这是场景列表
Think you can handle it?
你觉得能搞定吧？
We have rigged this entire valley of death with hidden cameras.
我们在整个死亡峡谷都隐藏好了摄像头
And I will be shooting as well, from unseen vantage points,
我也会从你们看不到的地方拍摄
so that every glorious moment is captured on film.
这样就能捕捉到所有精彩瞬间
And believe me, gentlemen, it will be glorious.
相信我，先生们，一定会十分精彩
If it looks real, chances are it probably is.
要是来真的，拍得也会更真实
You wanted to be actors.
你们想要成为好演员
You wanted to occupy the skin of another human being.
你们想要塑造角色
Well, get ready to occupy the skin of a terrified U. S. Infantry grunt,
那先变成一个恐惧下咆哮的美军士兵吧
surrounded by death, crawling up Satan's bottom.
生命受威胁，从死神的屁股下侥幸逃脱
There'll be ambushes, enemy fire, your own little personal slice of 'Nam.
会有伏击和敌军火力，和属于你们自己的越南体验
This radio goes to the chopper and the chopper only.
这个无线电话只能和直升机通讯
The chopper is God, and I am Jesus Christ, his son.
直升机就是上帝，我就是你们的耶稣，上帝之子
You are my chosen disciples.
你们就是我挑选的信徒
And no one gets to go home till we get the shots.
不拍完了谁也别想回去
Put on your war faces, gentlemen.
拿出你们士兵打仗的样子来
Now, let's go and make the greatest war movie ever!
让咱们拍成这部最伟大的战争电影！
- Yeah! - All right!
- 好！ - 好啊！
Yeah!
耶！
Not bad, Cockburn!
考蛋，装得挺像嘛
Not bad.
真不错
Wherever you are!
不管你在哪！
Wherever he is? Looks like he's all over the place.
他去哪儿了？看着好像天女散花了
Here we go.
就是这个
Must be an old French mine.
一定是老式的法国地雷
It's a remnant from colonial Indo-China. This jungle must be full of them.
原来的中印殖民地时留下的，树林里肯定到处都有
Don't you get it? He's messing with our heads.
还不明白吗？这是要让大家摸不着头脑
That's what all that playing God stuff was about.
所以他才说什么上帝
He's trying to get us to act good, save the movie.
他是想让咱们演得更好，拯救这部电影
He ain't playing God. He's being judged by him.
他才不是上帝，上帝已经惩罚他了
That's our objective. Complete the mission.
这些场景就是目标，咱们去完成任务
No offense, Kirk, I know you're the big fancy actor here,
柯克，无意冒犯你，我知道你是这里最大牌儿的演员
but I've done a lot more effects-driven event films than you. Okay?
不过我可是出演过很多视觉特效大片
And I think I can spot
我觉得还是认出来…
a prop head when I see one.
一个人头道具的
Oh, Jesus.
噢，老天
It's corn syrup, guys. Corn syrup and latex.
是玉米糖浆，伙计们，玉米糖浆和乳胶
Warm, blood-flavored corn syrup.
暖和的，带着血味儿的玉米糖浆
Oh, God.
天哪
Smoke and mirrors, guys. Welcome to the movie factory.
电影特效，欢迎来到电影工厂
Oldest trick in the book.
书上的老把戏了
He getting down now.
他总算说点有用的了
Oh, my God!
我的天哪
Whoa, look at me!
看看我！
You're going to get the shots,
“你们要拍完每个镜头”
and I'm going to make sure because I'm the director.
“作为导演我会确保这一点”
I'm from London. I direct plays.
“我来自伦敦，导演过歌剧”
Hey, Damien! We got our war faces on!
达门！我们已经变身军人了啊！
Look, I'm Dave Beckham.
看啊，我是大卫・贝克汉姆！
So, we gotta light these boys up today, huh?
我们今天要在他们身上放把火吧？
Blow some sense into these young men.
让这些年轻人长点见识
Hey, I don't want to come off as weird or anything,
你别认为我说这话很怪…
but I might be your biggest fan. Yeah.
我可能算得上你的头号粉丝了
Tropic Thunder. Kind of like my Catcher in the Rye.
《热带惊雷》就好比是我的《麦田守望者》
Yeah, I've never been in the military, per se,
虽然我本身没参过军
but I have lost an appendage in the line of duty.
可我也为了职责丢过些身体零件
Driving Miss Daisy, first studio gig.
《为黛茜小姐开车》首场摄影时弄的
Yeah.
是啊
It's a pretty cool sidearm you got there. What is it?
你这随身装备挺酷啊，叫什么？
I don't know what it's called.
我不知道它叫什么
I just know the sound it makes when it takes a man's life.
我只知道它夺人性命时发出的声音
Okay.
好吧
Damien, we're go for explosion.
达门，我们准备好了
Ready to kick the tires and light the fires on your say-so.
只要你下令，我就点火让他们爽歪歪
Damien, we're go for explosion.
达门，我们准备好引爆了
Do you copy?
收到了吗？
I got an itchy trigger finger here, and I'm ready to blow some shit up.
我都要忍不住了，已经准备好炸个狠的
All right, you happy now? Can we do the scene?
现在总该信了吧？可以开拍了吧？
Or do you need a formal invitation? Come on, let's go!
还是要给一个正式通知才行？来吧，咱们走
Here. Okay.
走吧，好了
"Scene 12, exterior, jungle clearing, day, ambush.
“第12幕，白天，林中空地，外景，埋伏”
"Four Leaf notices movement in the brush.
“四叶观察到了树林里的动静”
"A dozen guerrilla fighters can be seen moving in the tree line.
“看到一个游击小队在林中移动”
"Somewhere a mine explodes. " And you.
“一处地雷发生爆炸”，然后你
"I got a bad feeling on this one. "
“我有不祥的预感”
- Yeah. - No, that's your line.
- 我是有 - 不，那句是你的台词
- I got... Now? - Yeah, but scared. Like, scared.
- 我有…现在就说？ - 是啊，但是带上点恐惧
- "I got a bad feeling on this one. " - Dude, wait, like how?
- “我有不详的预感” - 等等，什么语气？
"I got a bad feeling on this one. "
“我有不详的预感”
- Okay. - Action. Go, come on.
- 好的 - 开拍，快点
I got a bad feeling on this one there, Fats.
我有不详的预感，胖子
Our asses don't get fragged in this bullshit valley,
要是出了这狗屁山谷，屁股还没炸烂
first thing I'm doing is paying my two bucks
我回去第一件事，就是花两块钱
so I can watch Brooklyn bust his cherry
去看布鲁克林以童男之身和一个…
Shit, Brooklyn be bagged and tagged before he get any cooch.
得了，还没搞成就被蒙面绑走了
He die, he probably die a coochless motherfucker.
他死了估计还是个小处男
Zip it, Motown.
闭嘴，底特律
Don't you worry, Brooklyn.
别担心，布鲁克林
You got a lot of days of fucking ahead of you.
以后你“干事”的日子还很多
Man, I'm thirsty.
渴死我了
Might as well have some of this Booty Sweat I got back in Danang.
不如喝点我在越南岘港带来的PP香汗饮料
Yo, asshole! This motherfucker's dead!
你们这群混蛋，那狗娘养的没命了！
Ain't no Criss Angel Mindfreak,
没有什么上帝耶稣的胡扯了
David Blaine trapdoor horseshit jumping off here!
这也没什么大卫的脱身魔术
Hey! You wanna get on the train here, or do you wanna ruin another take?
你是跟我们一块走，还是浪费下个镜头？
There ain't no goddamn takes, ain't no goddamn motion picture!
浪费个屁！早没有人摄影了！
- You sure? - Yeah.
- 你确信？ - 是啊
- Yeah? - For certain, man.
- 真的？ - 非常肯定
Then why are you still in character?
那你怎么还沉浸在角色里？
I know, but I don't have to tell you.
我自己明白，没必要告诉你
You don't know.
你不明白
Man, I don't drop character till I done a DVD commentary.
直到录完DVD评论音轨我才走出角色
You happy now? We're out of position for the effects!
这回满意了吧？大家都没走位呢！
Get down, fool!
卧倒，傻瓜
Didn't anyone read the script? This is the ambush!
没人读剧本吗？这是偷袭一幕
- This feels pretty real! - Exactly! Let's use it.
- 子弹还挺真的 - 是啊，好好利用这机会
Yeah!
耶！
Eat lead!
吃我的子弹！
They're busting caps like a motherfucker down there.
他们开枪射击打得跟疯狗一样
This is FUBAR. I say we juice them.
这回可玩疯了 我说咱们再加点“料”
- What do you think? - Juice them.
- 你觉得呢？ - 那就“加料”
Fuck you, Charlie!
越军去死吧！
Big-ass titties!
这可是强力奶头
Look at that, huh?
看看啊
And cut!
暂停！
That's the trailer right there.
预告片就这么拍出来了
Yeah!
爽！
- What do we do now? - Yeah.
- 现在咱们怎么办？ - 是啊
North. Man said to head north.
往北走，导演让咱们朝北走
- Did you see me shooting? - That's how we do. Good work, baby.
- 看见我开枪的样子了吗？ - 这才是真正的表演
I believed it.
说得没错
D'ang Kwook River.
前往当考河
I'm betting he's got more of these battles
我打赌他还会安排些这样的战斗
and Viet Congs rigged for us along the way.
沿路遭到越共偷袭什么的
Sergeant Osiris, get your men. Load and lock.
奥西里斯中士，集合士兵，整装待发
Real, baby, I'm real.
我可是来真的
Let's go! We got a lot of klicks to cover!
咱们出发，还要走几公里的路呢
Hump it up, gentlemen! Single formation.
扛起枪来，一字小队前进！
Don't dawdle now!
别磨蹭了
D-Rod, D-Rod, this is Puddingface. How are we coming on that hotplate?
大棒，大棒，我是胖脸，刚才场景拍得怎么样？
Something's up. I think we better drag ass back there.
肯定出了什么问题，咱们最好下去看看
Make sure Damien ain't forgot how to use his talkbox again.
确保这回达门别忘了怎么用对讲机
Yeah, baby, come on. Just a little taste.
宝贝儿，让我尝尝
- What are you doing, Jeff? - Fucking... Nothing, man!
- 你在干嘛，杰夫？ - 他妈的什么都没干！
- I'm eating jellybeans. - Wow, I love jellybeans. Can I please...
- 我在吃豆粒软糖 - 我也爱吃，给我点行吗
No, you can't have any fucking jellybeans.
不行，屁都不给你吃
They're mine.
都是我的
You think you're the only one who gets sick
你以为只有你不吃软糖…
when he doesn't have his jellybeans?
就浑身难受吗？
Boundaries, man. Fuck.
别贪得无厌，靠！
Hey. I didn't mean to show you up back there.
其实我刚才不是非要揭你短
It's just, I feel like we really need to set the example for the other guys.
我只是觉得咱们得给其他人树立榜样
It's gonna be tough,
这次会很辛苦
but I think Damien's gonna get some great shit out of us.
不过我觉得达门拍到了一些好镜头
Just wish I had a director like this on Jack.
真希望演杰克的时候，导演是他
On Jack. What? Jack? What you talking about?
演杰克？什么杰克？
- Simple Jack. - Oh, yeah.
- 《笨蛋杰克》 - 噢，是那个
Simple Jack, yeah. You went all out on that one, huh?
笨蛋杰克，尽全力演出的吧？
You did. Really swung for the fences, huh?
很不错，真是惊世骇俗
Thank you. Thanks. Yeah.
多谢，谢谢
Yeah, it was an intense experience, you know.
其实演杰克挺费心的
I just did the work.
我下了很多功夫
Watched a lot of retarded people. Spent time with them. Observed them.
花时间和很多弱智的人在一起，观察他们
Watched all the retarded stuff they did.
观察他们是怎么弱智的
Then again, I always found mere observation
其实我一直觉得
in and of itself is a tad rudimentary.
仅仅观察还是得来太肤浅
Sometimes, we gotta dig deeper to mine the true emotional pay dirt.
有时候，我们得深入挖掘人物的情感矛盾
Thus, we can diagram the source of the pain and then live it, you know.
发掘出痛苦的源头，亲身实践它
Yeah, yeah, live it. Yeah, exactly.
是啊，对，亲身实践
You know, there were times when I was doing Jack
你知道么 我演杰克那阵子
that I actually felt retarded,
有时候我觉得自己是真傻了
- like really retarded. - Oh, yeah.
- 好像真傻了 - 是啊
I mean, I brushed my teeth retarded,
我像傻子一样刷牙
- I rode the bus retarded. - Damn.
- 我像傻子一样坐公汽 - 我靠
In a weird way, I had to sort of just free myself up
我不得不以奇怪的方式让自己更豁达
to believe that it was okay to be stupid or dumb.
告诉自己当弱智或者傻子也没什么
- To be a moron. - Yeah.
- 当个低能儿？ - 是啊
- To be moronical. - Exactly, to be a moron.
- 大脑低能的人 - 对，低能儿
- An imbecile. - Yeah.
- 痴呆 - 没错
Like the dumbest motherfucker that ever lived.
就像有史以来最傻B的白痴？
When I was playing the character.
当我扮演角色时
- When you was the character. - Yeah, as Jack, definitely.
- 当你进入角色时 - 是啊，我是杰克的时候
Jack, stupid ass Jack.
杰克，蠢蛋杰克
Trying to come back from that.
你想从这个角色脱身
In a weird way it was almost like I had to sort of fool my mind
以一种奇怪的方式，我要说服我自己
into believing that it wasn't retarded,
相信自己其实没有这么傻
and by the end of the whole thing, I was like,
等快拍完的时候，我就好像
"Wait a minute, I flushed so much out, how am I gonna jumpstart it up again?"
“我入戏太久了，怎么回到原来的生活？”
- It's just like... Right? - Yeah.
- 感觉有点那个，是吧？ - 是啊
You was farting in bathtubs and laughing your ass off.
你连在澡盆里放屁、笑掉大牙都演了
Yeah.
是啊
But Simple Jack thought he was smart,
可笨蛋杰克认为自己是聪明人
or rather, didn't think he was retarded,
或者说觉得自己不傻
so you can't afford to play retarded, being a smart actor.
所以你不能以聪明演员的想法 去演一个笨蛋
Playing a guy who ain't smart but thinks he is,
他自以为聪明，其实是白痴
- that's tricky. - Tricky.
- 不好处理 - 是不好处理
It's like working with mercury. It's high science, man. It's an art form.
好比让神灵附体一样，那可是高深技术 那是艺术
- Yeah. - You an artist.
- 是啊 - 你是艺术家
- That's what we do, right? Yeah. - Yeah.
- 咱们就是在艺术创作 - 没错
Hats off for going there,
我为你脱帽致敬
especially knowing how the Academy is about that shit.
尤其是知道奥斯卡怎么评奖之后，你还能这样
- About what? - You're serious? You don't know?
- 什么怎么评奖？ - 你真不知道？没装傻？
Everybody knows you never go full retard.
大伙都明白不能演彻底的白痴
- What do you mean? - Check it out.
- 你是什么意思？ - 不信咱们数数看
Dustin Hoffman, Rain Man, looked retarded, act retarded, not retarded.
《雨人》里的霍夫曼长相很傻，表现很傻 但不是真傻
Count toothpicks, cheat at cards. Autistic, sure. Not retarded.
他会数牙签，玩牌时作弊 顶多算自闭症，可不是白痴
Then you got Tom Hanks, Forrest Gump.
《阿甘正传》里的汤姆・汉克斯
Slow, yes, retarded, maybe, braces on his legs.
脑筋慢，可能还有点笨，腿上戴着矫正支架
But he charmed the pants off Nixon, and he won a Ping-Pong competition.
可他一个电话让尼克松下台 还能赢得乒乓球比赛
That ain't retarded.
那就不是真傻
And he was a goddamn war hero. You know any retarded war heroes?
他还是战斗英雄 你认识什么白痴英雄吗？
You went full retard, man.
可你演的是大傻子
Never go full retard.
千万别演个大傻子
You don't buy that? Ask Sean Penn, 2001, I Am Sam.
还不信？你去问演《不一样的爸爸》的西恩・潘
Remember? Went full retard? Went home empty-handed.
想起来了？演成大傻子了，什么奖都没得
Oh, my God! Holy shit!
老天啊，真是见鬼了！
Good job, turd. You killed the director.
你个臭狗屎杀了导演
No, that's impossible, man.
不，这不可能
I rigged the whole tree line, and this is here.
我沿着树林线布置的，可他死这儿了
- He must have missed his mark. - Missed his mark?
- 他肯定忘了自己的记号了 - 忘了？
Yeah, this isn't me.
是啊，可这不怨我
Come on, let's bag and tag the bastard and get back to the hotel.
得了，找个袋子把他包起来回旅馆吧
- You're in a world of hurt, dumbo! - We're in a world of hurt!
- 你算完了，呆瓜！ - 咱俩都完了
- You're in trouble. - This isnt just on me!
- 就你自己 - 不能只怨我
- We're in a... We're together on this. - Bullshit.
- 咱们都有份儿 - 胡说
You're just gonna run away. You're gonna leave.
你就想这么溜走？
What happened to, "No man left behind, " okay?
还说什么“不扔下一个弟兄”
Just wait, just wait! Listen! Listen, okay?
你等等，听我说
- I don't wanna hear it. - Let me just be real with you, all right?
- 我才不听 - 我跟你说真的
I almost blinded Jamie Lee Curtis on Freaky Friday, okay?
拍《辣妈辣妹》时，我差点弄瞎了杰米・李・柯蒂斯 （也是《真实的谎言》女主角）
This shit will fucking ruin me!
再有这事儿，我就彻底完了
- Just get off me! You're pathetic. - No, I'm not.
- 放开我，你这可怜虫 - 我才不是
- Get off me! - You are not going back!
- 放开我 - 你不能回去！
- What the fuck? - Now wait a minute.
- 这他妈的是怎么回事？ - 等一下
So, what? We're just supposed to keep walking?
怎么办？咱们就这么继续走下去？
Try to stay in character. Remember, we're on camera.
大家保持角色状态，摄像机还对着我们呢
This thing's too heavy.
这太重了
I want the rubber one that the prop guy gave me.
我想要道具橡胶枪
Where's the fucking prop guy?
道具师都他妈跑哪去了？
How's it going with that map, chief?
头儿，地图看得怎么样？
- Can I have a look at it? - I got it.
- 我能看一眼吗？ - 我来处理
Yeah, Damien gave it to me, remember?
还记得达门把地图交给我吗？
Yeah, but he gave it to you for us.
是啊，可他是让你替我们保管地图
- Yeah. - Okay.
- 是啊 - 好吧
- I got it. - You got it upside down.
- 我拿着就行了 - 你把地图上下弄反了
Thank you.
谢谢
Letters go one way and the numbers another.
先看最上面字母，再看数字
Dude, I'm trying to... I got your back, man.
伙计，我只是…帮你留心
- Well, I'm cool. All right, I'm cool. - You are?
- 没事，我自己能行 - 你行？
Is your character dyslexic?
你演的角色有阅读障碍吗？
- No, my character's not dyslexic. - So you a cartographer.
- 没有 - 那你就是个画地图的了
I'm tired, I want to go home.
累死我了，我想回去
Why, so you can get back and make Fatties: Fart 20, or some shit?
干嘛？回去继续拍《肥仔之家第20屁》？
It's Fatties: Fart Two, there's no... Hey, you wish you had a Fatties franchise.
是《第2屁》，你想要肥仔之家授权吗
- What? - It's Fatties: Fart Two.
- 什么 - 是《肥仔之家 第2屁》
- Yeah, you do. - I don't want no Fatties franchise,
- 你需要授权的 - 我才不要
- I got a diamond toilet. - Your stupid-ass commercials.
- 我连厕所都镶着钻石 - 你那是傻屁广告
You're all fucked up, man, you look tired.
你看起来糟透了
You look like you bumped your head or something,
看着好像你脑袋被东西撞了
so I came over to see if you're fucking all right, that's all.
我是过来看看你还好么，没别的意思
- Yeah, why don't you get on point? - I'm on point right here.
- 是吗，那你怎么不当领头的？ - 我正要说这件事
... my farts are fucking more beautiful than...
…我的屁好听多了…
You still got that shit upside down.
地图还是拿反了
The numbers help, man, the numbers...
看数字坐标，有用的
The letters go across the top and then the numbers.
先看地图最上面的字母，再看数字坐标
- Want the map? - Yeah, I want the fucking map.
- 想要地图吗 - 是啊，我想看这破地图
Well, you can't have it, 'cause Damien gave it me.
想得美，达门是把地图给我看的
You wish you had my farts, my farts are fucking music.
你要能像我那样放屁就好了 我的屁是音乐
All right. That's enough.
行了，够了
Everybody's obviously a little bushed from all this humping.
看来经过刚才的激烈运动 大家都有点累了
So take a chow break. Chow break!
还是给自己喂食吧，吃饭了！
But stay alert.
保持警惕
Remember, Charlie don't care if you're on break or not.
记住，越军才不管你们是不是在休息
All right, that's lunch. Coming back to the same scene afterwards,
好了，该吃午饭了，回头接着拍
"Lost in the goddamn jungle. "
“丛林迷失”的一幕戏
Captain Simple Jack.
笨蛋杰克上尉
Fuck you.
去你的
I fucking hate movies.
恨死拍电影了
This is bullshit. I don't wanna be in this shitty movie.
这是在胡搞，我可不想拍这种烂片
No! That's my jellybeans! No!
不行，把我的豆粒软糖还给我！不！
Kid, grab the bat! Please! Shit!
小子，抓住蝙蝠！求你了！靠！
- Yo, man, I got a Bust-A-Nut. - You go to hell! There he is.
- 算了，我这儿有高潮坚果棒 - 你去死吧！它在那
God damn it! Okay. Where'd he go?
我靠啊，跑哪去了？
You little piece of shit! I'm gonna fucking rip your wings off!
你个小烂屎，回头把你翅膀扯下来
Sanducci. Hold up, man, keep it on the down-low.
三达祺，别动，小声保密 （把三达斯基读成了意大利口音）
I don't really gotta piss. I'm trying to talk at you, man.
我不是来尿尿，而是想跟你聊聊
Bait, I need bait.
诱饵，我需要诱饵
You went to boot camp, right? You can read a map?
你参加过新兵训练营吧？会看地图吧？
Yeah, I think so.
应该能行
I know Speedman got everyone convinced we out here
我知道快男让大家深信我们跑到这鬼地方
making Planet of the Apes on YouTube or some shit, but I don't buy it.
在拍能上Youtube的《人猿星球》或什么鬼东西 可我不信
You wanna step on a real landmine? You wanna die?
你想踩着真地雷吗？想死吗？
You wanna get shot by a real motherfucker?
想被狗日的真地打死？
- Keep looking ahead, man. - No, of course not.
- 向前看，伙计 - 我当然不想
Trying to get home, man.
我也是想回家
Got a big job coming up next year.
明年我还有个大角色要演
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
- 是吗？ - 是啊
It's about Abe Lincoln and John Wilkes Booth when they were both young.
林肯和他的刺杀者年青时候的事儿
- Oh, wow! - Yeah.
- 牛啊 - 嗯
- That's a classy picture. - Dude, you kind of look like Abe.
- 肯定是部好片子 - 伙计，你挺像林肯的
Slap a beard on you.
脸蛋糊上点络腮胡子就成
- What's your fucking name? - Really? It's Kevin.
- 你到底叫什么？ - 我像？我叫凯文
- Kevin Sandusky. - Yeah.
凯文・三达斯基
If I can put that map in your hands, can I count on you?
我要是把地图交给你，能够信任你吗
- Well, yeah, I guess you can. - Dynamite. I'm out.
- 行，我想可以 - 好小伙，那我走了
That smelled just like bologna for some reason.
闻起来好像腊肠
Is anyone gonna fucking help me get this fucking thing?
他妈的就没人帮我捉住这鬼东西吗？
Why are they even out in the daytime?
大白天的怎么会有蝙蝠
I'm gonna level with you, bro. I don't need to pee. I need to talk to you.
跟你说实话，我不想尿尿，只是跟你谈谈
Lazarus is gonna torpedo the movie.
拉扎勒斯他想要破坏电影
He's way out on a limb with this character,
他自己的角色都演不好
and I think he's getting cold feet.
我想他越来越胆小了
And the men respect you, 'cause you went to boot camp
大伙也都看得起你，因为你去过新兵营
and rehearsal.
还自己排练过
- Can I count on you, Kyle. - It's Kevin.
- 我能信任你吗，凯尔 - 我叫凯文
Good.
好吧
If you want I could give the map a look-see.
需要的话，我可以帮你看地图
- I'll handle the map. - Okay.
- 我看地图就行了 - 好的
You stick with the program, we get this movie in the can,
你按照计划走，咱们肯定能把电影拍完
I'm thinking there could be a Teen Choice Award in it for you.
估计你还能得个“青少年选择奖”
You have that potential. They'll slime you, the whole deal.
你有这潜力，孩子们会追捧你，就这么回事
- Yeah, that's wicked. - Good.
- 听起来不错 - 那就好
There it is! Yeah, now you're dead!
在那儿呢，你死定了
You O. D. 'd!
你吃药吃多了
Hold up now, Jeff.
你等等，杰夫
Fucking hell!
真他妈该死！
What the hell, Jeff? That's a bat, man!
你搞什么鬼？那是个蝙蝠
I don't have any more jellybeans.
我没有豆粒软糖了
You land there!
在那儿降落！
Wow. Look at these ruins.
看看这废墟
- Where the hell are we? - D'ang Kwook River.
- 我们到底在哪？ - 当考河
That so? How do you know that? How you sure?
真的？你怎么知道的？你确定？
Only one way to find out, dude. Let's go.
伙计们，检验办法只有一个，咱们走
Yeah. I'm not feeling so good right now. Seriously, my skin hurts!
我有点不舒服，说真的，我皮肤特别疼
Enough from the peanut gallery! Into the water, ladies!
别老在雅座里呆着了，下水吧，小妞们
No, man. Let me take a look at that map right quick.
等等，让我看一眼地图，很快的
Why is everybody all obsessed with the map?
你们怎么都惦记着地图啊？
'Cause we're tired of being your trail donkeys!
因为我们厌倦了像个傻瓜似地跟在你后面
Acting like you some one-man GPS!
好像你是什么真人GPS似的 （GPS:全球卫星定位系统）
God damn it! We lost! We fucking super lost, man!
我靠！咱们迷路了！他妈的彻底迷路了！
Tell him, McClusky. Tell him what time it is.
麦考斯基，告诉他几点了 (他长得像“麦考斯基”3人另类摇滚乐队的歌手)
I don't believe you people.
真没想到你们这些人怎么这样
What do you mean "you people"?
你说“你们黑人”什么意思？ （“你们这些人”英语里往往特指黑人）
I think what Tugg means is...
奋力 其实想说的是…
No, look at his eyes, man.
别解释，你看他眼睛
... you people, you actors. You people... - Look at them beady, white devil eyes.
- 我是说你们这些演员 - 你看他那邪恶的白色水泡眼
I gotta get back to the hotel, for real!
我必须得回旅馆，真的！
- Hell, no! - Silence!
- 没戏！ - 闭嘴！
Chill! All right? Just chill it.
都给我冷静！行吧？
Now, let's go get those Viet Congs.
现在，去找那些越共们
- "Viet Cong"! - What?
- “越共”！ - 什么？
It's "Viet Cong. " There's no "S. " It's already plural.
是“越共”，不是“越共们”，越共已经指多人了
You wouldn't say "Chineses. "
好比不能说“中国人们”
All right, that's enough of this insubordination!
行了，别跟咱们的领导抬杠了！
If the machine breaks down, we break down.
咱们核心垮了，大家也活不了
Hey, man, you know how in Rambo I, he was big but a little puffy
你知道在《第一滴血1》里，兰博还有点肥肉
and then Rambo II, he got all shredded up?
可到了《第一滴血2》，他全是肌肉块了？
- Yeah. - That's kind of how you look right now.
- 知道 - 你现在就那样
- Yeah? - Not Rambo I but II.
- 真的？ - 不是第一部而是第二部
- Really? - Yeah, when he was cut up.
- 真的吗？ - 对，愤怒兰博那样
I'm not that... I mean, that's what I'm going for, but you know...
我不是…我当然想变成那样，可…
Come on, dude. You more shredded than a julienne salad, man.
得了，你可比切成条的色拉还有型
- Thanks. - What's the secret, dude?
- 谢谢 - 你有什么秘诀吗？
- It's a diet. I'm just dieting. - Really?
- 是食谱，我在控制饮食 - 真的？
'Cause I'm trying to come up a little, but it's just... lt's tough.
其实我也想长点肌肉，可不容易
- You look good. - Any tips?
- 你看着挺好的 - 来点建议？
- What? - Any tips, you got?
- 什么？ - 给我点建议？
There's, like, the pineapple...
比方说，菠萝之类的…
- Give me that goddamn map! Fuck you! - Hey!
把破地图给我！去你妈的
- All right, now!
现在好了
What it is, Sikorski? Tell us where we really at.
怎么说，斯考斯基？我们究竟在哪儿？ （他的名字又被读成了波兰口音）
That's fucking bullshit! It's a chump move.
胡扯个屁！
We just getting a second opinion, doc.
我们只想听听不同意见，假博士
We're going the wrong way!
咱们走错了
- Damn! - Son of a bitch.
- 靠！ - 混蛋
God! I think we were supposed to be doing this,
天哪，我想咱们本来应该这么走
and instead we did this.
结果却这么走了
Shit, shit, shit, shitty shit, shit!
我靠！我靠！我靠靠靠！
Think you can get us back to that drop zone, boy?
你觉得咱们还能回到降落的地方吗？
This is not cool!
这可糟了
Maybe.
应该能行
This is insane!
这么做太愚蠢了！
Are you really going to abandon this movie?
你们真要放弃这部电影了？
We're supposed to be a unit!
咱们应该亲密团结啊！
Suck my unit!
亲我老二去吧！
All right, fine.
算了，好吧
- I'll finish it by myself. - You go be all you can be, man.
- 我自己拍完 - 你爱咋地就咋地
Tugg, you have no idea where you're going!
奋力，你根本不知道你这是要去哪儿
Yes, I do!
当然知道
I'm going to, "Exterior, rain forest, dusk.
我要去拍“热带雨林外景，傍晚”
"Smash cut to Four Leaf, who treks alone through a frightening jungle. "
“镜头忽然对准四叶，他正穿过骇人丛林独行着”
Suck on that unit, Kirk!
亲亲这情节去吧，柯克！
Come on, men. Let's get home.
来吧，伙计们，咱们回家吧
Hello, Mr. Mantis. You're beautiful.
你好，螳螂先生，你真漂亮
Now, if you recall that whole hullabaloo
你如果回想起那阵子
where Hollywood was split into schisms,
好莱坞分成两派
some studios backing Blu-ray Disc, others backing HD DVD.
一些公司吵吵着支持蓝光DVD 另一些支持HD DVD
People thought it would come down to
人们都以为最后取决于…
pixel rate or refresh rate, and they're pretty much the same.
像素速率或刷新率，其实这两个概念没什么区别
What it came down to was a combination of gamers and porn.
不过真正起作用的，是做游戏和拍A片的怎么选
Now, whichever format porno backs
得A片者得天下
is usually the one that becomes the most successful.
A片支持的才是牛B的
But, you know, Sony, every PlayStation 3 has a Blu-ray in it.
再比如索尼的Playstation 3也支持蓝光
You talking to me this whole time?
这么半天你在跟我说话啊？
I was talking to whoever was listening to me.
谁愿意听都行
Jesus Christ, man!
天哪
Booty Sweat.
PP香汗饮料…
It's cold! It's freezing. I'm fucking cold.
好冷！冷死了，他妈的冷死我了
You want my flak jacket?
我把防弹衣给你？
What, are you insane? It's boiling! It's like a sweat lodge out here!
你有病啊？我烧开水似的在冒汗！洗桑拿一样
Keep the volume down on that bitching, Flatch Adams.
发牢骚小声点，放屁・亚当先生 （98年喜剧《心灵点滴》男主角名字的恶搞）
I gotta take a fucking 12-pound shit!
我想拉上10斤屎
- How we doing? We making good time? - We're making good time,
- 怎么样？咱们顺利吗？ - 很顺利
but there's no way we make it over that ridge before sundown.
不过在天黑之前不可能翻过那座山
All right, fellas, we're gonna make camp, rest up!
好吧伙计们，咱们扎营，休息！
- Oh, God. - Y'all might be in for a treat.
- 天哪 - 估计我能请大家吃晚饭
You know, back before the war broked out,
想当年，战争爆发以前
I was a saucier in San Antone.
在圣安东尼奥城，我是法式调味师
I bet I could collar up some of them greens.
我估计能找点野菜
Yeah, noodle some crawfish out the paddy, yo.
从庄稼里现磨面做点小龙虾面条，哥们儿！
And maybe some crab apples for dessert, now, you hear? Hell, yeah!
再拿点野果做点心，你们听见了？他妈的爽！
Hell, yeah!
他妈的爽！
That's how we all talk. We all talk like this, suh! Yes, suh.
黑人就这么说话，我们都这么说话，操
Yeah, get some crawfish and some ribs.
“弄点小龙虾和排骨，我爽”
You're Australian! Be Australian! Excuse me, Kangaroo Jack.
你是澳大利亚人！说自己人的方言！抢钱袋鼠！ （03年电影《抢钱袋鼠》）
I get excited about my foods, man.
想起做饭我就沉不住气
Die!
去死吧！
No!
不！
Dude, dude, what the hell is going on here? Where are we?
伙计！这究竟是怎么回事？咱们在哪？
I have no idea.
我不知道
I've never been outside the States.
我从没离开过美国
Wait, what? Are you fucking kidding me?
等等，说啥？你他妈的逗我玩呢？
Did you make this whole goddamn thing up?
你自己胡编的整个剧本？
Dude, were you even in the fucking service?
伙计，你是不是都没当过兵？
Yes. Of course. Coast Guard.
我当过，海岸巡逻队
- Coast Guard. - Sanitation Department.
- 海岸巡逻队 - 环境卫生部
Oh, my God! You're a fucking garbage man!
我靠！你他妈的是个倒垃圾的！
Damn it. F. L. Tayback lies to me and the whole goddamn U. S. Of A.
见鬼，四叶・泰背对我和整个美国撒了谎
I wrote the book as a tribute! I'm a patriot!
我写这书是为了歌颂美军，我是爱国人士！
Yeah, you're the Milli Vanilli of patriots, okay?
是啊，你就是爱国者里面假唱的米力瓦利 （米力瓦利是90年红极一时的乐队，其实一直在假唱）
You lied about fighting the Vietnam War.
你撒谎说参加过越南战争
It's like punching the American flag in the face, God damn it.
你这就像对准美国国旗打了一拳，靠！
God, and to think I believed in you!
而且我还相信了你！
- I don't wanna be next to you. - Writers lie all the time.
- 我可不想挨着你坐！ - 作家们都在说谎
Can I be tied to another post? Okay.
能给我绑到另一个柱子上吗？好吧
- Rick? - Tugg.
- 瑞克？ - 奋力
I killed one, Rick.
我杀了她，瑞克
The thing I love most in the world.
世界上我最喜欢的东西
Vivica, get off the line now!
维威萨，别听我们谈话
A hooker. All right, you killed a hooker.
你杀了妓女，好的，你把妓女杀了
Calm down. Here's what you're gonna do.
冷静，接下来这么做
Get your hands on some bleach,
手上涂点漂白粉
some hydrogen peroxide and a shitload of lime.
一些双氧水和一大坨石灰 （这样起的化学反应其实会将手严重烧伤）
No, a panda.
错了，是个熊猫
I killed a panda.
我杀了一只熊猫
Amanda? Come on, dude.
阿曼达？得了，伙计 （阿曼达与“一只熊猫”发音相近）
I mean, that's probably not even her real name.
这肯定不是她真名
No, a panda!
错了，是只熊猫
A panda?
是只熊猫？
A sweet, cuddly,
是只可爱、看着就想抱的
vicious little panda.
邪恶的小熊猫
Jesus Christ, Tugg! Man, don't scare me like that!
老天，奋力！别这么吓唬我
It's beautiful here.
这儿挺漂亮的
You on the set?
你还在外景地吗？
I am the set.
我现在就是外景
All right, man. Hey, how's the TiVo working out?
别扯了，伙计，那个“替你录”怎么样了？
Screw TiVo.
让它去死吧
I'm way beyond TiVo.
我不在乎“替你录”了
Last I checked, they hadn't hooked it up, though.
我上回去查看，他们还没接好呢
Hadn't hooked it up? No TiVo?
没接好？没“替你录”？
It doesn't matter anymore.
这全都无所谓了
I've moved on.
我换地方了
Where have you moved on to?
你换哪去了
Another agency?
你换了家经纪人公司？
Who's with you?
谁跟你在一起？
It's Nick Stevens, isn't it? That little fucker.
是尼克・史蒂文吧，那个混蛋 （这个人是快男扮演者的真实经纪人）
You are still my client, Tugg Speedman! I am getting the TiVo!
你还是我的客户，奋力・快男 我这就帮你搞定“替你录”！
Jacket's on, I'm out the door!
我穿上夹克了，马上出门！
Tugg?
奋力？
Please don't fire me.
别解雇我
I did it, I did it!
我成功了，我成功了！
Vivica, what do I have scheduled this afternoon?
维威萨，我下午有什么安排？
- Two and a Half Men taping. - Shit.
- 录电视剧《好汉两个半》 - 我靠
Cancel it.
取消吧
And get me Tugg's Tropic Thunder contract.
把奋力的《热带惊雷》合同拿给我
I'm going to Grossman's office, I'm playing the card.
我去格罗斯曼的办公室，把话讲明白
Okay.
好的
Oh, mama. Thirsty.
我的妈呀，渴死了
He doesn't look too good.
他脸色可不好
Must drink, so I can throw something up!
必须喝水，才能呕吐点东西出来
No, no. Don't drink that water! That water's like a petri dish!
别喝那水！那水像细菌培养皿里的！
No, don't!
别喝！
Alpa, do you have any Booty Sweat?
阿尔帕，你还有PP香汗饮料吗？
Yeah, get him chugging on some of Alpa's ass water.
是啊，让他咕嘟点阿尔帕的屁股汤
That'll bring him around. It's a cure-all.
那能让他恢复意识，那可是万能解药
Man, what you coming out in movies for anyway?
伙计，你干嘛来拍电影？
Did you need another revenue stream?
为了多条财路？
For your information, my revenue stream
你给我听明白，我现在的财路…
currently generates $2 million a year
可以让我每年拿出两百万
in charitable contributions for my community.
给我的社区做慈善捐助
- Hot damn. - And why am I in this movie?
- 真牛B啊 - 我为什么拍这部电影？
Maybe I just knew I had to represent,
可能因为我想要做个表率
because they had one good part in it for a black man
因为有个好角色是个黑人
and they gave it to Crocodile Dundee.
结果还给了“鳄鱼邓迪” （86年票房冠军《鳄鱼邓迪》主角是澳大利亚白人）
Pump your brakes, kid. That man is a national treasure.
你赶紧打住，“鳄鱼邓迪”可是澳大利亚的国宝
I just wanted to throw another shrimp on your barbie.
“我还想在烤肉架子上添条大虾” （“鳄鱼邓迪”主持的澳洲旅游节目宣传口号）
That shit ain't funny.
这屁话可不好笑
Hey, fellas! It's hot! We're tired! It stinks!
又热又累，你们别闹了
I'm just fucking with you, Kangaroo Jack!
我就跟你过不去，抢钱袋鼠！
You know that's a true story? Lady lost her kid.
这是真事儿，那个女士丢了小孩
- You about to cross some fucking lines. - Guys, relax and stuff.
- 你差点就嘲笑过头了 - 你们别闹了
You know what? Fuck that, man!
我他妈的才不管！
I'm sick of this koala-hugging nigger telling me...
受够了这考拉熊搂着的黑鬼告诉我…
For 400 years,
四百年以来…
that word has kept us down.
白人用这词压制着咱们（黑鬼）
What the fuck?
你他妈说什么呢？
It took a whole lot of trying just to get up that hill.
为了过这个坎，咱们付出了巨大代价
Now we up in the big leagues,
现在咱们结成联盟
getting our turn at bat.
前赴后继
Long as we live, it's you and me, baby.
只要活着，咱们荣辱与共
That's the theme song for The Jeffersons. You really need help.
这是《杰弗逊一家》的主题歌，你真该看医生了 （美国80年代的黑人家庭喜剧）
Yeah. Just 'cause it's the theme song, don't make it not true.
就算是歌词，也揭示了真相
You know what? I'm gonna tell you what's true.
我告诉你什么是真相
I'm gonna tag you back. You better believe that, baby.
真相就是我会报复你的，爱信不信
Guys! Hey, guys!
伙计们，伙计们！
Jeff, stay away from that animal.
杰夫，离那动物远点
I'm gonna bite his hide. I need...
我要咬它的皮，我需要…
I need to wear his stomach skin like a unitard.
我想要把它的胃做成我的紧身衣
Ain't nobody doing nothing to no one or body!
大家屁都不准动！
Now, if Mr. Portnoy is feeling a little flu-ish, don't wanna walk,
要是波特牛先生染上了点流感，不想走路
put him up on that cloven-hoof animal!
那就把他放到带蹄子的动物身上
We got ground to cover!
还要赶路咧
All right, POW camp, scene 67.
好了，越南战俘营，第67幕戏
Bring it on, Cockburn!
有本事来啊，考蛋导演！
Maybe he's not, you know, Ridley Scott or something,
虽然他不像雷利・斯科特那么牛 （《美国黑帮》《角斗士》的制片人）
but I think Renny Harlin's a tremendous filmmaker
不过我觉得雷尼・哈林也很了不起 （《特工狂花》《八面埋伏》的制片人）
like, Adventures of Ford Fairlane, you know,
像90年的《神探奇兵》就很不错 （雷尼是本片导演，同时也是演员）
as far as an Andrew Dice Clay vehicle goes, it's pretty decent.
男主角安德鲁把车一开，很不错
And Cliffhanger. Cliffhanger's incredible.
他导演的《绝岭雄风》十分了得
As far as the whole like, man against nature type of movies go,
那种人对抗大自然的剧情推进
it's absolutely amazing.
绝对让人惊叹
Shut the fuck up!
你他妈的给我闭嘴！
Who send you here?
谁派你来的？
Tayback, John, Sergeant, United States Army.
我是美国陆军泰背中士
Serial number 694529987.
编号694529987
Perhaps some hot tea will make conversing
也许来点热茶能让咱们的对话…
a little easier.
轻松一点
My leader's not quite as cordial.
我们领导可算不上热情
Look, what? I just thought you might like some hot tea
你这是怎么了，我还以为你要喝茶
- in order to calm your nerves. - Tayback, John, Sergeant,
- 来冷静一下 - 泰背中士
United States Army, 694529987.
美国陆军，编号694529987
And here's a little message from my Uncle Sam.
我替美国大叔给你捎个话
Dude, you all right?
伙计，你没事吧
Man you totally leaned into that.
你整个人都靠过去了
I was pulling it back and you just came in too...
我本来想收招的，可你离得太…
Hey, it was an accident, man.
纯属意外
Come on, good. You want to keep going?
接着来，好的，你想继续吗？
- Let's go. - Get up.
- 来吧 - 起来！
I rather rot in your V. C. Jail!
我宁愿烂死在你们越南监狱里！
I'll never bend to your will! You scum! You scum!
我绝不让你如愿，你个坏蛋！
Now say this and go to the beginning again,
你说完后咱们再从头来一遍
let's do the tea part, okay?
再来喝茶那段戏，好吧？
Dude, I hope you're not pissed.
伙计，希望你别生气
I see moss on both sides of that tree.
我在那棵树两边都发现了苔藓
Well, you know, maybe if I wasn't the only one at boot camp...
看来，不只我一个参加过新兵训练营啊…
My belly really hurts, you guys!
我肚子疼死了，伙计们
I'm not joking around, I'm nauseous.
我没开玩笑，我恶心死了
Let me off, I gotta puke! I don't wanna die like Hendrix!
放开我，我要吐了！我可不想像亨德斯那样死 （Hendrix亨德斯是摇滚歌星，死于吸毒过量）
All right. All right.
好了，好了
Are you okay, Jeff?
你还行吗，杰夫？
I'm awesome.
感觉好极了
Holy shit!
我靠！
Okay. Everyone, down, down, down.
好了，大家都隐蔽！
Man. Now I'm tripping.
看来我错了
That looks like the POW camp from out the script, yo.
好像真是剧本上说的越南战俘营
Speedman was right?
难道快男说对了？
I don't think so.
我不觉得
Look at the cooking vats, the armed guards.
看那些煮东西的大桶和拿枪的守卫
Looks like a heroin processing plant.
看起来像海洛因加工厂
We were in that chopper for hours.
咱们在直升飞机上飞了几个小时
I don't even think we're in Vietnam anymore.
我觉得早就不在越南国内了
- Fuck. - Shit. We ain't even in 'Nam?
- 靠 - 见鬼，咱们都出越南了？
No, most likely Myanmar or Laos.
是啊，更像在缅甸和老挝
What the fuck is Laos?
老挝是什么东西？
It's the Golden Triangle.
是金三角
Oh, fuck. We're dead.
我靠，咱们死定了
No one gets out of here. I saw it on TV.
谁都逃不出去，电视上看到的
Fucking boats, airplanes, UFOs and shit, they all just vanish!
轮船飞机，外星飞碟之类的全都消失
Yo, that's the Bermuda Triangle, dumbass.
那是百慕大三角，白痴
This is the Golden Triangle.
这是金三角
It's the world's hard drug superhighway.
世界上烈性毒品的集散地
How do you know that?
你怎么知道这些？
It was a really long trip. I read the in-flight magazine.
旅途太长了，我读了读飞机上的杂志
Cut!
停拍！
Oh, Jesus!
天哪
What do you see, man? I'm blocked.
看到了什么？我被挡住了
Damien, cut!
达门，停拍了！
Hey, Damien, cut!
达门，停拍！
They got Speedman.
他们抓住快男了
And it doesn't look good.
情况不妙啊
I am Tran.
我是陈老大
You are a trespasser in my poppy fields.
你闯进我的罂粟地盘了
You are D. E. A. Scum!
你们美国缉毒署的混蛋！
Were there some re-writes that I missed?
难到重写了剧本我没看见？
Do you want to die?
你想找死吗？
- Do you? - No!
- 想吗？ - 不！
Please, don't hurt me!
请…别…杀…杀…我！
Say that again.
你再说一遍
Please, don't hurt me.
不要杀我
No! Like you did before! Say it!
不是，像你刚才那样说一遍！
Say it!
说啊！
Please, don't hurt me!
请…别…杀…杀…我！
- What? - You are Simple Jack.
- 什么？ - 你是笨蛋杰克
You saw Simple Jack?
你看过《笨蛋杰克》？
We love the tale of this man, Simple Jack.
我们喜欢他的故事，笨蛋杰克
We do not have many luxury here.
我们这儿没什么娱乐
And Simple Jack is the only movie we possess.
《笨蛋杰克》是我们仅有的电影
You got the VHS.
噢，是录像带格式的
We've watched it many, many times.
我们看了很多很多遍
You should've got Oscar.
你应该得奥斯卡奖
Well, you know. It's...
其实，能够…
Just to be nominated...
能够提名…
You were nominated?
你获得提名了？
No, no, no. I wasn't nominated.
没有，我没有获得提名
I'm just saying that to have been nominated would have been nice.
我是说，能获得提名就很满足了
It's just... lt's very political. You have to take out ads...
奥斯卡评选也要搞政治，你得登广告…
- Shut up now! - Okay. Okay.
- 现在闭嘴！ - 好的，好的
So, are you going to
那么，你要…
let me go, or...
放我走，还是…
No. We'll hold you for ransom.
不行，我们要拿你换赎金
Much more money now!
现在能要价更高了！
He's in a meeting.
他在开会
Yeah, I know. In about two seconds with the Pecker.
我知道，2秒钟后他就跟我开会了
I'm gonna rip your fucking tits off.
我要把你乳头扯下来
You wanna talk about trouble? That's trouble.
想谈谈麻烦事吗？麻烦来了
What do you need, Peck?
想要干什么，佩克？
No, more like what do you need, Les?
不干什么，想要个你正缺的，雷斯
Glasses?
眼镜？
What?
什么？
So you can read the Tropic Thunder contract
这样你就能看清楚《热带惊雷》的合同
that guarantees my client, Tugg Speedman,
满足我客户 奋力・快男 的要求
some form of digital video recorder on location.
给他一台数字视频录放机
- Huh? - I can't believe you let him in.
- 啥？ - 你怎么能让他进来
Look, fuckstick, I'm incredibly busy, so why don't you get the hell out of here
听着，傻B，我可是非常忙 你最好快点滚出去
before I snap your dick off and jam it into your ass?
省了我扯断你老二塞进你屁股里去
No, not you, Helen.
海伦，我刚才没说你
But I will rip your tits off if you don't get me those theaters.
但你要搞不定那几家电影院 我把你乳头扯下来
Perfect.
正好了
Hey, Tuggernuts, I've got you on speakerphone.
笨蛋奋力，电话现在是用外音喇叭
I'm standing here with Les Grossman,
我正和雷斯・格罗斯曼站在一起
and he is dying to tell you why he's apparently wiped his ass
他很想告诉你，为什么把“替你录”条款…
with the TiVo clause from your contract.
…当擦屁股纸的
We are Flaming Dragon.
我们是火龙帮
Speedman is with us now.
快男现在在我们这儿
For 50 million, you will get him back.
花五千万，你就能把他要回去
- Are you gonna get those... - Who is this?
- 你能不能把… - 你是谁？
- And how did you get this phone? - We are Flaming Dragon!
- 你怎么拿到的电话？ - 我们是火龙帮！
Simple Jack belong to us now.
笨蛋杰克现在在我们手上
He does, does he?
是吗，你想得美
Let me tell you something, shitbird.
我跟你说，你个琶
I've never even heard of your little agency.
我从没听说过你们这个破经纪人公司
But if you think you can poach my client...
可要是你认为能抢走我的客户…
Send $50 million, or you no see Simple Jack again because we kill him.
给我五千万，否则跟笨蛋杰克永别，我们就杀了他
This is Les Grossman. Who is this?
我是雷斯・格罗斯曼，你是谁？
This is Flaming Dragon!
我们是火龙帮！
Okay. Flaming Dragon. Fuckface.
好的，火龙帮，JB脸
First, take a big step back and literally fuck your own face!
你先后退一大步，对着你的脸狠狠地操过去！
Now, I don't know what kind of pan-Pacific bullshit power play
我不知道你们代表泛太平洋的…
So whatever you're thinking, you better think again.
别轻易闹事炸刺
Otherwise, I'm gonna have to head down there,
否则，我就过去
and I will rain down an ungodly fucking firestorm upon you.
给你们来一场核爆炸天谴
You're gonna have to call the fucking United Nations
到时你们就得给他妈的联合国打电话
I am talking scorched earth, motherfucker!
我说的是烧焦你们，狗娘养的！
I will massacre you!
给你们来场大屠杀！
I will fuck you up!
把你们全都搞死！
- Could you find out who that was? Go. - Yeah. Yeah.
- 能查出来这是谁吗？ - 可以
You wear these. More like Simple Jack teeth.
把它戴上，这更像笨蛋杰克的牙
Okay.
好
Hey. Look, I know you're a big fan, and that's great...
我明白你是我的超级粉丝，很好…
Put teeth in!
把假牙戴上！
Now do movie.
现在照着电影演
The whole movie?
整部电影？
I can't. I don't know the whole...
演不了，我不知道整个的…
You perferm! You perferm or die!
快演！不演就杀了你！
Monkey swine!
你个耍猴的！
Pa.
爸
More stupid!
再演傻点！
Pa, why you gotta make me feel bad?
爸，为啥你日…日…让我这么难受？
You saw what I saw.
你们也都看见了
Tugg Speedman is dead meat if we don't do something soon.
咱们要是不干点啥，奋力・快男就死定了
Yeah. We could do something by getting our asses back to the hotel,
如果快点回到旅馆，还能干点什么
which is in the other direction!
可咱们走反了！
Ain't right.
不能回去
What would've happened in The Great Escape
如果《大逃亡》里的史蒂夫和伙计们…
Well, that's what that movie was about. They were escaping. They ran away.
可这电影就是拍的逃亡啊，他们最后跑了
I'm trying to agree with you. The point is they did something.
你没错，我只是强调他们努力了
Then what are we supposed to do, huh?
那咱们该怎么办？
'Cause he's cleaning a gun with no bullets. Yeah, that's a plan.
他的枪里都没子弹了还擦什么擦，真是烂计划
I'm just like a little boy, playing with his dick when he's nervous.
我其实像个心里紧张就乱摸鸡鸡的小男孩 （回应上一句，因为他的“枪”没子弹了还在擦）
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
大伙等一下，等一下
I got an idea. This might be a little crazy.
我有个主意，可能有点疯狂
Crazy's better than nothing.
疯主意也比没有强
Back in '98, I did a low-budget titty comedy for Skinemax.
在98年，我给麦克斯公司拍过低成本色情喜剧 （麦克斯有线电视网，因色情节目多，人称Skinemax）
- Sex Camp. Remember it? - Yeah.
- 《情色野营》，记得吧？ - 记得
Anyway, me and the campers from the uncool camp
我们这帮丑男营地队的人…
had to break into the rich girl camp.
要想办法闯进美女营队的地盘
So, what we did,
我们是这么做的
we built a catapult out of logs and underwear,
用木头和内裤造了一台投石机
and they shot us over the wall, and we parachuted down.
我们被射过围墙，再跳伞着陆
Look,
听我说…
you guys, we already know the plan.
伙计们，咱们其实早就有现成计划了
Are you fucking kidding me? I'm giving you gold.
开玩笑吗？我的主意是金玉良言
We do it just like in the book, Chapter 26, the Wet Offensive.
咱们就照着书里面第26章“雨季进攻”那样做
The book of Tropic Thunder.
《热带惊雷》这本书啊…
Yeah, did you guys read the book?
你们都看过这书吧？
The flap, I read the back flap and saw the pictures.
看过外皮儿，书封底，见过照片
Well, it's okay. It's exactly the same as in the script.
那也没关系，这跟剧本里也一样
Cool.
酷！
You guys all read the script, right?
你们至少看过剧本吧？
I don't read the script, script reads me.
我不看剧本演，是剧本照着我演
What the hell does that even mean?
这他妈的又是什么意思？
What you getting at with the books, scripts? Spit that shit out, man!
你对书和剧本了解多少？有屁快放！
All right. The Wet Offensive.
好吧，“雨季进攻”
Osiris and Fats go undercover as a diversion.
奥西里斯和胖子乔装来吸引敌人注意
Motown and Brooklyn sneak in via the river.
底特律和布鲁克林两人从河塘溜进去
Yeah. But those dudes was trained soldiers.
可他们是训练有素的军人！
Yeah!
是啊
And we trained actors, motherfucker.
但咱们是训练有素的演员，你个傻B
Time to man up. And I ain't gonna sugarcoat.
该开始行动了，我就不说好听的了
Some of us might not even make it back.
咱们有些人可能会回不了家了
What do you mean? Like not on the same flight?
什么意思？一趟飞机还带不走所有人？
Alpa and I's already wearing earth mama's natural night camo.
阿尔帕和我都自带着天然牛B迷彩服 （因为他们是黑人）
- Cool it, Benson. - Sorry.
- 少说不碍事，本森 - 抱歉 （本森是80年代电视剧黑人主角）
We gonna scout, get a plan together. We ain't back in 20, come looking.
我俩先去侦察，回头大家一起想计划 20分钟还没回，就去找我们
We are Flaming Dragon.
“我们是火龙帮”
Okay.
好的
Flaming Dragon's a heroin manufacturer.
火龙帮是个制造贩卖海洛因的组织
They're responsible for an eighth of the drug trade in Asia.
他们负责亚洲八分之一的毒品交易
- Huge profit margin. - Guys!
- 非常高的利润率 - 大伙们！
Would somebody please let me know what the game plan is?
谁能告诉我咱们的计划是什么？
Peck! We have it handled.
佩克，我们尽在掌握中
Please, don't interrupt. Everything's under control.
别插嘴，尽在掌握呢
I got it. Got it.
我明白，好的
- Les Grossman. - We not get money yet.
- 我是雷斯・格罗斯曼 - 还没有收到钱
Price now 100 million!
现在价钱是一亿了！
You pay now, or tomorrow Simple Jack die.
现在不交钱，明天笨蛋杰克就死定了
Great. Let me get this down.
好啊，让我先记一下
100 million.
一亿元
Wait! I got a better idea.
等等，我有个更好的点子
Instead of 100 million,
与其给你一亿
how about I send you a hobo's dick cheese?
不如给你送点流浪汉鸡巴奶酪？
Then you kill him! Do your thing! Skin the fucking bastard!
然后你就杀了他，随你便，扒皮也行！
Go to town, man! Go to town!
玩得尽兴点，玩得尽兴！
- No... - In the meantime, and as usual,
- 不行… - 同时，与以往一样
go fuck yourself!
去操你自己吧
- No. - We don't negotiate with terrorists.
- 不行 - “我们不跟恐怖分子谈判” （最早是副总统切尼在911后所说）
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! Hey, hey, are you insane?
你疯了吗？
- I think I could've done that better. - I thought it was good.
- 我觉得还能更好点 - 很不错了
They're gonna kill him!
他们会杀了他！
And?
还有呢？
"And?"
“还有”？
It's a cold, hard world. Shit happens.
世界残酷得很，总会有倒霉蛋
We'll weep for him, in the press.
我们在新闻发布会上为他掉眼泪
Set up a scholarship in his name.
以他的名字冠名某个奖学金
Eventually, and I'm talking way, way down the road,
最后，我是说最最后
we file an insurance claim.
起草一个保险索赔书
Preferably before the end of the fiscal year.
最好在年度财务结算之前
Actually, the claim alone would net us more than the movie would lose.
其实，单这个索赔就能补偿电影赔的钱
You can't be serious.
你没开玩笑吧
You kick in the door to my house,
你自己送上我的家门口
all ants in your pants, sucking my left nut to get a TiVo scrap
坐立不安，舔我左边蛋蛋 就为了拿到个“替你录”
for the third runner-up Sexiest Man Alive 1998,
和1998年的时尚最性感男人季军 （《人物》每年评选，类似《时代》年度人物）
and you're asking if I'm serious?
居然问我是不是在开玩笑？
Let's face it.
面对现实吧
The kids aren't dressing up as Scorcher for Purim anymore.
现在小孩们在犹太普林节不打扮成“热天”了 （《热天总动员》主角快男）
Speedman is a dying star,
快男是过气明星
a white dwarf heading for a black hole.
像白矮星要变为一个黑洞
That's physics. It's inevitable.
物理规律决定，不可避免
We've been handed an incredible opportunity here, Peck.
佩克，我们可是给你个大好机会
The universe is talking to us right now.
老天要让我们告诉你他的旨意
You just gotta listen.
你必须听从
See, this is the good part, Pecker. This is when the job gets fun.
佩克，这才是精彩部分 也是工作变得有趣的时候
Yeah.
是啊
Ask and you shall receive.
开口请求神的旨意，然后接受
- All right. - You play ball, we play ball.
- 对 - 你先开口，我们配合
I know you want the goodies.
我知道你想要好东西
Welcome to the goody room.
欢迎来到好东西的密室
You paying attention? 'Cause I'm talking G5 for the Pecker.
注意听，我说的可是给佩克一架G5商用飞机
That's how you're gonna roll.
你就乐得打滚吧
No more frequent flier bitch miles for my boy.
不再有飞机乘客在你耳朵边唠叨了
Yeah!
耶！
Playa.
我是泡妞高手
Playa!
泡妞高手！
Big dick playa.
大老二的高手
Swinging past your knees!
老二长过你的膝盖！
Big dick, baby.
大老二，宝贝儿
Yep.
是啊
Or you can grow a conscience
要不你就花上5分钟
in the next five minutes and see where that takes you.
培育良心，然后看它会把你带哪去
Let me get this straight.
我就有话直说吧
You want me to let my client of 15 years,
你要让我15年的客户
one of my best friends,
也是我最好的朋友
die in the jungle, alone, for some money and a G5?
让他孤独地死在丛林里，就为了G5飞机和钱？
Yes.
是的
A G5 airplane?
一个G5商用飞机？
And lots of money.
和一大笔钱
Playa.
我是泡妞高手
Yeah!
耶！
Smack it up, flip it, rub it down!
你就用嘴含住，轻轻舔它，反复摩擦吧！
But Mama take care of Jack a lot.
可妈妈那么照顾杰克
How many more sleeps before she wakes up again?
她还要睡多久才能醒过来？
Sorry, Jack.
对不起，杰克
She in heaven now.
她去到天堂了 （中式英语）
Damn! I thought the movie was bad.
靠！我还以为那是部烂片
She sleep forever.
她永远睡睡了 （中式英语）
To the man's credit, he's actually eased up on the retard throttle.
是配角的功劳，他实际上缓冲了杰克的傻气
And now that's added a balance, and the audience can connect.
达到了某种平衡，这样就吸引住了观众
I mean, this is Theater 101, but, you know, he's had a tough road.
其实这是演戏的基本常识，不过他还在慢慢磨练
He'll become a naturalist.
以后会更得心应手的
- Yeah. - Break down the aesthetic distance,
- 是啊 - 雅俗共赏
then the...
然后…
Told you I'd tag you back.
跟你说过我会报复你的
Can I tell you that I'm sorry
我能对你说声道歉吗
for any offense I might've caused, man?
如果我以前冒犯了你的话？
- I just got caught up in... - In being a dumbass?
- 我就是有点摆脱不了… - 成为一个半残？
I guess so.
我猜是吧
Why you still doing this Chicken George shit, I have no idea.
我真不明白你为什么还在演“鸡公乔治” （Chichen George鸡公乔治，黑人DJ）
- Neither do I. - It's beyond me.
- 我也不明白 - 理解不了
- You confused.
- 我也理解不了 - 你自己迷糊了
- I am a little confused. - I know.
- 是有点迷糊 - 我知道
But are we cool?
那咱俩就讲和了？
Not really.
还没有
Hey, man.
嘿，伙计
- How's it going? - Good. Yourself?
- 进展怎么样？ - 还不错，你呢？
Hey, so, if it's no big deal,
那个…要是影响不了什么…
I think I'm just gonna hang back here for the mission.
这次任务我就不去了
Watch the stuff.
我就在旁边看着好了
- Is that cool? - What? No!
- 这样行吗？ - 什么？不行！
We need you, Jeff.
我们需要你，杰夫
What are you talking about?
你这是什么意思？
Okay, look, man.
听我说
- I got something to tell you. - Okay.
- 我有些事情得告诉你 - 好啊
You know those jellybeans I was eating?
你知道我吃的豆粒软糖吗？
Well, they werent jellybeans, okay?
其实，不是什么豆粒软糖
- They were drugs. - Really?
- 是毒品 - 真的？
I get down there near the mother lode, I am done. I'm jonesing bad, man.
我要是到了毒品宝藏附近，绝对控制不住 会非常想要的
I'm gonna fucking do all the heroin in the fucking world.
我会把所有的海洛因都他妈的吸干净
If you guys wanna make it through this thing, you gotta strap me to a tree.
你们要真想让事情办成，就把我绑到树上
- Are you serious? - Yeah, I'm serious. Literally, a tree.
- 你说真的？ - 真的，毫不夸张，给我绑到树上
And you can, no matter what, you can't fucking untie me until it is done,
不管发生什么，完事儿之前也别给我松绑
until it is out of my system.
直到我想都不想了才行
I'm gonna say, "Hey, man, I'm cool. It's cool.
我可能说“伙计们我没事儿了”
"I'm finally better. I'm finally better. Untie me. "
“我总算好了，松开我吧”
Don't listen to me! Anything I fucking say is a lie!
别听我胡说！我说什么鸟语都是在骗你！
You got it!
一言为定
Goodbye, Mama!
再见，妈妈！
Now you can have ice cream in heaven.
现在你能在天堂吃上冰激凌了
I'll see you tonight, when I go to bed, in my head movies.
今晚我睡觉的时候会在我脑中放的电影里遇见你 （“做梦”的弱智说法）
But this head movie makes my eyes rain.
可这回的电影会让我的眼睛下雨 （“哭泣”的弱智说法）
Dang. Short-bus is taking some real hits.
靠，小脑残这下挨得可不轻
- They got him on the move! - That's torture, man.
- 他们把他带走了 - 这可是要折磨他了
Okay. That's where they keeping him.
好，知道他被关在哪儿了
I gotta get cracking on my costume.
我得开始弄我乔装的衣服了
Say, are you good with a needle and thread?
你做针线活还行吗？
Hell, yeah.
靠，当然行
Alpa Chino chinos sold more than five million pairs last spring at the Gap.
在GAP服装店的上个春季 “阿尔帕・奇诺”牌棉裤卖了5百万套
- I sewed them patterns myself, baby. - Let's roll out.
- 图案都是我自己缝的 - 咱们走吧
It's a little twig man Oscar.
这是树枝做的奥斯卡小金人
I'm going to call you Half Squat.
我就叫你小半蹲
And you can call me
你可以叫我…
Papa.
爸爸
Wow, look at all those stars.
瞧瞧这些星星
Really makes a guy feel pretty small.
真让人感觉自己很渺小
This could be the last time we look at these stars.
可能是我们最后睁眼看星星的机会了
Man, that's beauty.
真美啊
Nights like tonight make a man wonder what it's all about.
这样的夜晚，能让人反省自己这辈子都为了什么
Hey, you guys. Anybody got some bug spray?
伙计们，谁有杀虫剂吗？
Don't ignore me!
别不理我！
Stick it out, man. We're gonna get through this.
坚持到底，过去劲就好了
- Hey, Kirk? - Yeah?
- 喂，柯克 - 什么？
Are you still dating Jennifer Love Hewitt?
你还在跟詹妮弗・休伊特约会吗？
'Cause I think she's hot.
我觉得她可是超级性感
No, that was just some tabloid conjecture.
没有，那都是小报瞎猜的
Hey, guys, I'm good. I made it through. You can untie me now.
伙计们，我挺过来了，把我解开吧
Funny, huh?
真够滑稽的…
The circus life 280 days a year on location.
演员的生活，一年当中280天都在外面转
It's hard to find a girl that can hang with that, you know?
其实挺难找到一个能忍受这点的姑娘
Not one worth keeping, nohow.
谁也留不住，没办法的事
Hey, Radar? Evans?
有雷达杀虫剂吗？埃文？
No, it's Kevin.
我叫凯文
Kev, whatever the fuck. Come over here.
凯五，不管你他妈的叫什么，给我过来
I didn't tell you, but Fatties: Fart Three is coming down the pike,
我没告诉你，肥仔之家 第3屁马上开拍了
and there's a role in there for you if you come over and untie me.
你要是把我解开，我就把一个角色让给你
Jeff, you're just going to have to tough it out.
杰夫，你得表现坚强点
Your mother's a cankerous whore!
你妈就是个浑身溃烂的婊子！
Jesus, man.
天哪
Hey, man.
伙计
Remember way back when I said your mother was a cankerous whore?
刚才我说你妈是烂婊子的时候…
I'm sorry, man. I did not mean that. She's not.
抱歉，我不是这个意思，她才不是
How about you, man?
你呢，伙计？
You got some little minx waiting for you on the other side of tomorrow?
明天在家那边有个风骚姑娘等着你吗？
Me?
我？
I've barely even had a girlfriend, and...
我都没谈过女朋友…
I was really hoping I'd get laid when this movie came out,
我其实特想拍完电影后就能找人上床
but that's not gonna happen.
好像不太可能
What about you, Masterblaster?
你呢，爆破小子？ （一个系列动作游戏的名字）
You got a certain someone you trying to get with back in the States?
老家那里有你想要得到的人吗？
What, Alpa Chino? He's like 10 girls deep, 24/7.
阿尔帕・奇诺？他可是整天整夜都有10个妞陪着
No. You missing me, man.
你理解错我的意思了
I'm talking about something special. Big difference.
我是说的某个特别的人，与众不同的
How about it?
有吗？
Yeah.
有
Yeah, there is.
确实有
Well? What's the skinny? Y'all been on a date or what?
有什么内部消息？你们约会过了吗？
No. I mean...
没有，我…
I always wanted to, but I guess I just never had the courage to ask.
我一直想约会，不过可能永远不会有胆子去问
It's... lt's complicated.
事情…很复杂
No! It's simple as pie, man.
得了！跟做馅饼一样简单
You plant your feet in the ground, you look her square in the eyes, you say,
你在地上站稳了，瞪着她眼睛说
"Hey, baby, you and me's going on a date. " That's the end of story.
“宝贝，咱们约会吧”，这就结了
- What's her name? - Lance.
- 她叫什么名儿？ - 兰斯
"Listen here, Lance... "
“听我说，兰斯…” （兰斯是男子名）
Lance? What the fuck did I just hear? Lance?
兰斯？我刚才听成什么了？兰斯？
- Did you say "Lance"? - No!
- 你说“兰斯”？ - 没有
- That sounded like "Lance. " - No, I said "Nance. "
- 听着像兰斯 - 我说的是南斯
- That's what I said, "Nance. " - It sounded like "Lance. "
- 我说南斯  - 听着就是兰斯 （南斯也有娘娘腔的意思）
Look, I'm Alpa Chino, okay?
我可是阿尔帕・奇诺，好吧？
I love the pussy! All right?
“我爱BB”，明白？
Lay your ass back down and look at the stars.
屁股坐稳了，看你们的星星
When you wrote I Love Tha Pussy
你写那首“我爱BB”的歌时
was you thinking of dangling your dice on Lance's forehead?
是在想像你的蛋蛋在兰斯脑门上乱晃吧？
Oh, hell, no! What? Come on. Look.
我靠，说什么呢？得了吧
- Man, everyone's gay once in a while. - I'm not gay!
- 伙计，人人都会有一时的同性恋倾向 - 我不是
This Hollywood.
好莱坞里不稀奇
How about we all get back to work?
还是聊正事吧
- Okay. Cool. - This is ridiculous!
- 好了，行了！ - 真是可笑！
We got a big day tomorrow. Let's get focused.
明天还有大事要做，大家别瞎分心
Alpa, if you untie me, I will literally suck your dick right now.
阿尔帕，你要给我松绑，我现在就去吸你DD
I told you, for the last time, I love the pussy!
我跟你说最后一遍，我喜欢BB
I'll cradle the balls, stroke the shaft,
我会捧住蛋蛋，按摩棒棒
work the pipe and swallow the gravy.
来回运动，咽下肉汁
Get it over here, buddy. Let's do this.
你赶紧过来，咱们开始做吧
Okay, so, what's the plan?
好，计划是什么？
Are you gonna talk Vietnamese to those dudes?
你跟他们说越南话？
No. No. Mandarin Chinese.
不，我说普通话
Which, from what I can tell, is what they speaking down there.
我听出来他们在这儿说汉语
How the hell do you know Chinese?
你怎么会说汉语？
Land of Silk and Money with Gong Li. Second Globe, third Oscar.
和巩俐演过《丝绸黄金之地》 我因此得了第2个金球奖，第3个奥斯卡
Prepped for that one by working in a Beijing textile factory for eight months.
为此我花了8个月在北京纺织厂干活体验
That might be our ride.
估计这次能成
The straps are too tight!
皮带太紧了！
Shut your mouth and follow my lead.
闭嘴，跟着我走
The straps are cutting off my circulation!
皮带捆得我血都不流通了
Fuck you!
- 你什么都不是 - 我靠啊
Laz, don't let him take me off the yak.
拉扎，别让他把我从牛身上放下来
Bitch whore! Fucking hate you!
你个婊子！恨死你了！
Okay.
好吧
All right.
好的
That looks like it could be the munitions hut right there.
看来那里是装弹药的小屋了
I'm gonna try to find Speedman in the main building.
我到大房子那里找快男
I don't know Chinese but it sounds like your improvising is for shit.
我不懂汉语，可听起来你在说大便的事儿
Oh, fuck!
我靠！
Get over here!
过来啊！
- What are you guys doing here? - He has hands.
- 你俩怎么在这儿？ - 他有手的！
- He killed Damien. - Bullshit!
- 他杀了达门 - 胡说！
- He blinded Jamie Lee Curtis. - Almost!
- 他还弄瞎了杰米・李・柯蒂斯 - 差点弄瞎！
What are you talking about? Damien stepped on a old landmine.
你们胡说些什么？是达门自己踩上老式地雷了
Sweet. Thank God.
太好了，谢天谢地
- We busting Speedman out. - Speedman's here?
- 我们这就去救快男 - 快男也在这儿？
I take it y'all are doing the Wet Offensive from the book.
我想你们是在演“雨季进攻”那出戏
I can give y'all a diversion.
我能帮你们转移视线
I got enough shit here to light this place up like it's the Fourth of fucking July.
这一大坨火药估计能把这儿炸得 像国庆节放礼花一样
Yes, your farm.
是的，你的农场（英语）
American?
美国佬？
My farm?
我的农场？
Oh, shit.
我靠！
Here's my motherfucking farm!
这他妈的就是我的农场！
Yeah! Chicka-chickaw, baby!
耶！咯吱喀嚓，宝贝！
Kwan-Lo!
狂了！
I'm a lead farmer, motherfucker!
我是农民头头，王八蛋们！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, keep your head down!
耶！耶！把头低下！
Keep your head down on the ground!
把头贴到地上
Nobody move or I do the little big guy!
谁也别动，要不我就干掉这个小老大
That's right, we running this program now, J. P.
干得好，咱们控制局面了，杰夫・波特牛
Now show me where the drugs are.
现在带我去找毒品
What the fuck?
你他妈的怎么回事？
That ain't the plan!
这不在计划里！
Dont judge me!
别指责我！
He's got a real serious problem.
他的问题可真严重
Hey! Hey, you!
嘿，你！
Take off your clothes!
把衣服脱了！
What do we do now?
现在怎么办？
Stick with the plan. Find Speedman.
按着计划走，去找快男
Alpa, keep this clown posse down. Come on now.
阿尔帕，控制住这群小丑，咱们走
Y'all heard the man. Be suede, don't move!
听着了吧，都给我温顺的呆好了别动
Fuck your do-rag. Fuck your do-rag.
你个烂头巾！
- Door! - One, two, three!
- 准备开门 - 1，2，3！
I go high, you go low.
我去上面，你到下面
Get down. Get down! Get down! Chow Yun-Fat, get the hell down!
趴下，趴下！周润发们给我趴下
If I see one more head pop up, it's gonna be bullet Whac-A-Mole.
谁敢再抬头，我就一枪打死你个捣乱地鼠
Come on, come on!
快点，快点
- Smoke grenade. - Don't drop it now.
- 烟雾弹 - 别掉地下
Here.
给
- What's this? - I don't know what it's called.
- 这是什么？ - 不知道叫啥
I just know the sound it makes when it lies.
我只知道它点着以后，满嘴胡诌是什么声音 （借用了原来四叶的话，用lies替代light讽刺他）
Don't move, Matchbox, or I will shoot you.
别动，火柴盒，要不我打烂你
I'm gonna put on this thing. Don't move.
我把这衣服穿上，你别动
I can still see you.
我还看得见你
Tugg!
奋力！
Tugg?
奋力？
Gotcha.
找到你啦
Roll your shit up, man. We going home.
你赶紧卷铺盖走人，咱们回家了
Home?
回家？
But I'm doing five shows a day for a standing-room-only crowd.
可我在这里一天演出5场，场场爆满
Don't you get it? I already am home.
你不明白吗？这里就是我的家
All right, now, dude, you gotta get it...
得了，伙计，你得…
My son gave this to me.
我儿子送给我的
- That's your stick buddy? - His name is Twigman.
- 这是你的树枝朋友？ - 他叫树枝人
Does he wanna come with us?
他想跟咱们一块走吗？
Get down! Get down! Get down!
趴下，趴下
Maybe y'all heard of me. Y'all heard of Alpa Chino? No?
你们肯定听说过我 阿尔帕・奇诺都知道吧？
I love that pussy, hell, yeah, hell, yeah
“我爱BB，哦耶，哦耶”
They're not your demo, dude.
跟他们炫耀可不是时候
Come on. Six motherfucking VMAs, baby.
还没想起来？6届MTV奖
Two BET Awards. Alpa Chino.
2次黑人娱乐电台奖，阿尔帕・奇诺
Like him in Carlito's Way?
学他演《情枭的黎明》？
Hey, yo, you know what? Speak English. I don't speak that stuff.
你给我讲英语，我不懂你说什么
What're you sayin'? Huh?
你胡说啥呢？
Devil's Advocate. Dog Day Affernoon.
《魔鬼代言人》《热天午后》
Cruising. Sea of Love.
《虎口巡航》《午夜惊情》
Real Al Pacino.
真正的阿尔・帕奇诺
Get the fuck down. That's a whole different dude altogether.
给我趴下，那完全是另一个家伙
What you doing? What you doing? Don't touch that gun.
你想干啥？别碰那枪
Don't do it! Don't touch that gun!
别动，别碰那枪！
On my momma, if you touch that gun...
我的妈呀，你要是敢动…
- Oh, shit, it's on! - Over here!
- 见鬼，开打了！ - 从这走！
- What're you doing? - I'm gonna give these boys
- 你要干什么？ - 我给这帮小崽儿来个…
a Hanoi high-five.
河内式的空中击掌
Shadow me, Pinocchio!
掩护我，皮诺曹！ （童话人物，说谎了鼻子就变长）
Smoke!
来点烟雾！
Oh, shit!
我靠啊！
Jeff, don't!
杰夫，别那么做！
It doesn't matter what I do.
我做什么都无所谓了
I'll always be a screw-up. No one'll ever respect me.
我这一辈子都是一团糟，没人会瞧得起我了
That is not true, you are not a screw-up! You make so many people laugh.
你说的不对！你不是废物！你让那么多人开心
They only laugh at my farts.
他们只是在笑我的屁
Jeff, we really need to go now!
杰夫，咱们得走了！
This is all I deserve!
我就应该这个下场！
Laugh at that, you bastards!
笑个屁，混蛋们！
Hilarious! Hilarious!
好笑吧，好笑吧！
Let's move. We only have 16 hours before they wake up.
咱们快走，他们再有16个小时就要醒过来了！
Sounds like the dinner bell's ringing.
看来吃晚饭的铃响了
These assholes are gonna be crawling in here ready to fucking eat us.
这帮混蛋一会就会爬过来生吃了咱们
There. All right, you keep six right here.
好了，你在这儿望风
Come on, let's go.
来啊，咱们走了
Come on, what are you guys doing? Let's get out of here!
你们这帮家伙在干吗？快点走啊
He's on tilt status.
他正在迷离的状态
Same thing happened to me when I played Neil Armstrong in Moonshot.
在演《月球探测器》的阿姆斯特朗时 我也这样过
They found me in an alley in Burbank
他们在澳洲伯班克小路上找到了我
trying to re-enter the Earth's atmosphere in an old refrigerator box.
我正想要乘一个旧冰箱来重新进入大气层
What're you talking about?
说什么呢？
Come on, fellas, we really need to go.
快点，伙计们，咱们真得走了
Daggomit, Blamtucky, I ain't re-programming a VCR.
天老爷叨唠啥，这不是翻录录像带那么简单 （goddamnit一词前后互换，blat mucky也类似）
Give me the flame thrower. You gotta start the chopper.
把火焰喷射器给我，你快去启动直升机
- No, fuck that! Just give me this. - No time! I'll take care of this!
- 别管了，去他妈的，交给我 - 没时间了，我来顶着
All right. Give me your hooks.
好吧，把你的铁钩给我
Don't worry, I'm not gonna put them on again.
别担心了，我不会再戴上了
- Just give me your goddamn hooks. - All right. Here.
- 快把铁钩给我 - 好，给你
Get those boys back to the bird, pronto!
你快点把这帮孩子带回直升机去啊
Shit! Enough!
靠啊，够了！
Fake shit!
假冒伪劣！
Fuck!
我靠
Go get your guys! Get them to the chopper!
快去找你的伙计们，带到直升机那儿
I'll take care of these yahoos!
我来对付这些野蛮人！
You're gonna focus up now, motherfucker, and say it.
你一定要集中精力，混蛋，跟着我说
- "It's me, Tugg!" - It's me, Tugg.
- “我是奋力” - 我是奋力
That's right! Now, Tugg who?
好，那奋力是谁？
- Tugg who? I don't know. Who are you? - Me?
- 是谁？我不知道，你是谁？ - 我？
I know who I am!
我知道我是谁！
I'm a dude playing a dude disguised as another dude.
我这个家伙要扮演一个 假扮成另一个家伙的家伙
What?
啥？
You a dude that don't know what dude he is!
你这家伙连自己是谁都不知道
Or are you a dude who has no idea what dude he is
或者你才是不知道自己是谁的人吧
and claims to know what dude he is...
你还得扮成另一个人…
What the fuck are you guys talking about?
你们他妈的说什么呢？
... by playing other dudes?
- …才能说出来了解自己？ - 我知道我是谁！
Or scared of who?
应该是害怕谁吧？
- Scared of who? - Come on, guys. We really need to go!
- 我怕谁？ - 来吧你俩，咱们快走！
Scared of you.
你怕你自己
- Jesus. - What's going on?
- 天哪 - 到底怎么了？
The dudes are emerging.
全部人格都开始显露出来了
He's right, you know.
他说得对
I am not
我不是…
Sergeant Lincoln Osiris.
…林肯・奥西里斯 中士
We gotta roll out.
咱们快走
Nor am I Father O'Malley.
我也不是神父奥马力
Or Neil Armstrong.
也不是阿姆斯特朗
I think I might be nobody.
我想我可能谁都不是
The insecurity level with you guys is ridiculous!
跟你们在一起可真没安全感
- Everybody's got issues! - Yeah, man, everybody got issues.
- 谁都有问题 - 是啊，每个人都有问题
Come on! You're Kirk Lazarus.
得了，你可是 柯克・拉扎勒斯
You're the whole reason I got into acting.
就是因为你，我才选择当演员的
I memorized every single monologue
我还在戏剧学校时…
you ever did when I was in theater school.
记得你说过的每一句独白
- Really? - Yeah. And look, Tugg!
- 真的？ - 还有你，奋力
I saw Scorcher I 24 times when I was in eighth grade.
我8年级的时候把《热天总动员1》看了24遍
That shit blew me away! I got high to that shit! You the man!
你那电影让我绝对震撼！爽死我了 你真是个爷们！
Yeah, man, Scorcher I was great. Let's get the fuck out of here!
是啊，《热天总动员》第一部很不错 咱们快点从这儿离开！
Tugg, Tugger, you're the last piece of the puzzle, buddy.
奋力，奋力，现在就差你了！
We need you! Your men need you! Are you with us?
你的朋友需要你！你跟我们走吗？
I'm a rooster illusion.
我是公鸡做的梦
Fuck it. We'll deal with him later.
他妈的，回头对付他
Let's move. Come on. Come on. Double time. Gotta go!
快点，快点，动作快点，走了
Come on, come on, come on.
快，快，快
Bingo! Move out.
太棒了！开始行动
Oh, God.
老天爷
Just say no to this, you drug-making midget.
学着对炸药说不，你个贩毒的小矮人 （“学会说不”是80年代反对毒品运动的口号）
Gotta hold on!
你要坚持住！
Four Leaf!
四叶！
You grew hands?
你长出手来了？
RPG, gentlemen!
伙计们，火箭推进式榴弹！
Where are you going?
你们这是去哪儿？
Oh, my God. I am moving to catering after this.
天哪，这活干完了我改行开饭馆去
My ass!
我的屁股！
Hey, yo! We gotta get our shit together, Tugg!
奋力你听着，咱们得快点收拾烂摊子
We gotta get his cracker ass to the chopper!
把他这屁神送回直升机去
Are you still crazy? We gotta get Candisky to the chopper!
你还糊涂吗？咱们得把坎迪斯基带回去
It's Sandusky.
他叫三达斯基
- Kevin Sandusky. - That's my name.
- 凯文・三达斯基 - 是我名字
You remembered my name.
你记得我名字 （第一次被大牌明星们说对名字）
Alpa, go help Cody.
阿尔帕，你去帮科迪
Portnoy, get Sandusky back to the chopper. Go!
波特牛，把三达斯基带回直升机，行动！
- I got him! - Let's go!
- 好的 - 咱们走
Let's get out of here!
快点离开这儿！
Hey, Leaf!
嘿，四叶！
- Leaf! - Yeah.
四叶！
Hit the plunger
等咱们的人一过桥…
- as soon as they clear the bridge! - Got it!
- 你就马上按下这活塞！ - 明白
Come on! Get in the chopper!
快点，上直升机！
- Come on! Move! - Kirk! Wait!
- 来啊，行动 - 柯克！等等！
Laz, I'm gonna blow the bridge!
拉扎，我要炸桥了！
Are you the special effects guy?
你是视觉特效师吗？
- You God damn right I am. - Fuck yeah!
- 没错 - 好啊！
Leaf's about to blow the bridge. Come on!
四叶就要炸桥了，快！
You don't have to! You don't have to! I'm staying.
你不用救我，我想留下来
No, I can't let you do that, mate. We gotta go.
我不能扔下你，咱们一起走
No, I'm telling you, I'm not being crazy. They'll listen to me.
我没有发疯，他们会听我解释的
I know it sounds weird, but I have a connection with them.
虽然听起来有点怪，可我跟他们有了感情联系
You're not doing tofu dinner theater for these motherfuckers. Let's roll!
你可不是给他们做饭后演出的，咱们走
- Get over here! - I have a son now. Little Half Squat.
- 快过来！ - 我有儿子了，名叫小半蹲
Who in crikey fuck is Half Squat?
他妈的又是谁啊？
He's my son. He's my boy!
我儿子，我的孩子！
He needs me. I have to go back to him.
他需要我照顾，我必须回去
You tell the world what happened here.
让外面知道这里发生的事
What happened here?
这里发生了什么事儿？
I don't know, but you need to tell them.
我也说不清楚，不过你得告诉他们
I got this.
我会处理好的
Tugg!
奋力！
You take care of the boys! I'll deal with these guys.
照顾好大伙，我来和他们说清楚
Where is he going? We're gonna fucking die!
他这是去哪？咱们都要死了！
Laz, come on. He joined the circus. Let's go.
拉扎勒斯，是他自己选择加入马戏团的，走吧
- You've got hands. - Yeah.
- 你长出手来了 - 是啊
- Fuck! You've got hands? - Come on!
- 靠！你本来有手啊？ - 快点！
- Get in!
- 快点 - 进来
- He's staying?
- 他留下了？
Go! He's a lost cause, mate! Get out of here!
走吧，没希望说服他了，咱们走
I was wrong! Blow the bridge! Blow the fucking bridge!
我错了！快炸桥！把这破桥炸了！
I got this.
让我来
Leaf, no!
四叶，不！
It's over! He's gone!
结束了，他死了
Cody! We gotta go!
科迪，咱们快走吧
Look.
快看
Think he's done.
他要不行了
Cover me!
掩护我！
- Come on! - Wait, come back!
- 得了！ - 等等，回来！
How do we cover him?
拿什么掩护他？
All right, game over. Come on, mate. Come on.
好了，游戏结束了，伙计咱们走
- You all right, man? - I'm cold.
- 你还好吗？ - 我身体冰凉
I can't feel my legs.
我大腿没知觉了
No, no, they're in a puddle, mate. See? There's a puddle right there.
瞎扯，腿泡在水坑里了，看着了？是水坑
- No worries. - Good.
- 别担心 - 太好了
Come on, we gotta split, man.
咱们快点走了，伙计
Hey! I want you to know something.
我想跟你说…
What?
什么？
I know who you are.
我知道你是谁…
You're my friend.
你是我的朋友
You're my brother.
你是我的好兄弟
But like a really cool brother, you know?
是那种真正的好兄弟
Like a brother where there was no animosity or...
之间没有任何仇恨和…
Don't look now, you got some real tears going.
眼见为实，你现在真的流泪了
Really?
真的？
That's the stuff that accolades are made of.
这才是能让你获奖的东西
Jesus, let's go, man!
天哪，咱们快走！
All right?
好吗？
Upsy-daisy.
起来喽
Come on! Come on! Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
快点，快点！咱们走！
Get in! Get in!
进来，进来！
Come on! Here we go!
好了，出发吧！
Tuggernuts! I got it!
笨蛋奋力！我拿到手了！
- Tugger! - Rick!
- 奋力！ - 瑞克！
What the fuck?
又他妈怎么了？
I got the TiVo!
我带来了“替你录”！
My friend wants a TiVo, my friend gets a TiVo!
我朋友想要的“替你录”！
Oh, shit!
我靠！
And the Oscar goes to...
获奖者是… （奥斯卡最佳男主角奖）
Yes! Tugg Speedman.
好啊！奋力・快男
"Tropic Blunder, The True Story Behind the Making
“《热带蠢雷》 有史以来最昂贵的战争片…”
"of the Most Expensive Fake True War Story Ever. "
“拍摄中的真实故事”
Yeah!
耶！
Eight Oscars, $400 million
8项奥斯卡奖，4亿美元收入
and you saved Tugg Speedman's career.
你还挽救了奋力・快男的演艺事业
I couldn't have done it without you, Slolom.
所罗门，没有你我肯定做不到
Really?
真的？
No, dickhead, of course I could.
才不是呢，白痴，没你一样
- A nutless monkey could do your job. - Well, I...
- 一个阉了的猴子都能顶替你 - 我…
Now, go get drunk and take credit at all the parties.
参加派对吧，喝个大醉 把功劳都记自己身上
- I would never do that to... - Joking.
- 我永远不会这么做… - 我在开玩笑
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 真的
Very... Okay, there he is.
那…太好了，真有你的
- There he is. Okay. - Go have fun.
- 真有你的，好的 - 玩得开心
All right. We're having a...
好的，我们会很…
Fuck, okay. Thank you, Les. Thank you. You have a good night...
不扯了，我真心谢谢你，雷斯，晚安
But seriously, a nutless monkey could do your job.
我说真的，阉了的猴子也能顶替你
Good. Thank you, sir.
好的，谢谢您，先生